[
  {
    "id": "d325de24-1fd5-4086-bbf4-9baa5602ddb7",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: We _____ to the city museum three days ago. 8. He _____ fishing three times a week because he _____\nspending time by the lake.\nB: Oh, how nice!",
    "options": {
      "A": "went / love\nA) can go",
      "B": "goes / loves\nB) went",
      "C": "is going / loved\nC) go",
      "D": "goes / is loving\nD) are going"
    },
    "answer": "goes / loves\nB) went"
  },
  {
    "id": "06bdc310-006a-445d-918c-269dab2a5284",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Nina _____ in the park alone yesterday morning and\n2. Victor _____ some bad news from Ted yesterday and she _____ a book.\n_____ sad.",
    "options": {
      "A": "can sit / reads\nA) is hearing / is becoming",
      "B": "sits / reads\nB) hears / becomes",
      "C": "is sitting / is reading\nC) heard / became",
      "D": "sat / read\nD) can hear / become"
    },
    "answer": "sat / read\nD) can hear / become"
  },
  {
    "id": "b2425cea-d881-4298-a19e-f2c66e6e6b57",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "The twins _____ an experiment in the lab these days,\n3. _____ she _____ your books back last week? so they _____ usually busy.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Can / bring A) did / were",
      "B": "Did / bring B) are doing / are",
      "C": "Does / bring C) can do / were",
      "D": "Is / bringing D) do / are"
    },
    "answer": "Did / bring B) are doing / are"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb821a83-c418-4c37-9a5d-3a9d0c27c23d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "They often _____ questions in meetings. They just 11.A: When _____ your clients sign the document?\nmake presentations.\nB: Four days ago.",
    "options": {
      "A": "didn't answer\nA) was",
      "B": "don't answer\nB) were",
      "C": "aren't answering\nC) did",
      "D": "can answer\nD) are"
    },
    "answer": "don't answer\nB) were"
  },
  {
    "id": "764a2cdc-f373-4070-88e6-a390a2e4f679",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I _____ my house last week, but it _____ dirty again\nnow. 12.Thomas _____ up in the morning and _____ his best\nclothes because that day was important for him.",
    "options": {
      "A": "cleaned / is\nA) is waking / is wearing",
      "B": "clean / was\nB) woke / wore",
      "C": "am cleaning / is\nC) wakes / wears",
      "D": "cleaned / was\nD) can wake / wore"
    },
    "answer": "cleaned / is\nA) is waking / is wearing"
  },
  {
    "id": "f6265d42-5b2d-44fe-9212-10c73e4c94eb",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Basil _____ an operation on his stomach last year and\nnow he _____ no problem with it. 13.Mandy _____ her arm two weeks ago and she _____\nnow.",
    "options": {
      "A": "can have / had\nA) broke / didn't write",
      "B": "had / has\nB) is breaking / doesn't write",
      "C": "is having / can have\nC) breaks / isn't writing",
      "D": "has / had\nD) broke / can't write"
    },
    "answer": "had / has\nB) is breaking / doesn't write"
  },
  {
    "id": "3295cecc-fa59-4862-9e82-e588dd60c0fb",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I _____ the window and _____ a deep breath before the\nexam yesterday. 14.Chris and Frances often _____ camping when they\nwere young, but now they often _____ holiday inns.",
    "options": {
      "A": "can open / can take\nA) can go / preferred",
      "B": "open / take\nB) wen't / are preferring",
      "C": "am opening / am taking\nC) are going / can prefer",
      "D": "opened / took\nD) went / prefer\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPast Simple ( Regular / Irregular Verbs ) Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "opened / took\nD) went / prefer\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPast Simple ( Regular / Irregular Verbs ) Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f726cea-3292-40a7-ada8-682ba550278f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "The police officer _____ the driver right now because 18.We _____ very hard last night to finish the project on\nhe _____ a traffic rule a few minutes ago. time, but it is weekend now and we _____ a break.",
    "options": {
      "A": "talked / broke A) work / had",
      "B": "talks / breaks B) worked / are having",
      "C": "is talking / broke C) are working / have",
      "D": "can talk / is breaking D) worked / had"
    },
    "answer": "is talking / broke C) are working / have"
  },
  {
    "id": "96f24151-b61a-4613-ad33-74e7ee1d6001",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "He _____ his homework but _____ it at home because 19.A: What _____ you tell Tom last night?\nhe left home in a hurry yesterday morning.\nB: I _____ him the truth.",
    "options": {
      "A": "did / forgot\nA) did / tell",
      "B": "is doing / forgets\nB) were / told",
      "C": "can do / is forgetting\nC) did / told",
      "D": "do / forgot\nD) were / tell"
    },
    "answer": "did / forgot\nA) did / tell"
  },
  {
    "id": "ec92edd2-c133-4eb5-9a8e-4247a4148a88",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "455_past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I always _____ up late in the past because I was\nunemployed, but I'm working now and _____ up early 20.A: Where _____ you go for a holiday last summer?\nto go to the office on time.\nB: We _____ to Portugal.",
    "options": {
      "A": "get / got\nA) did / went",
      "B": "am getting / get\nB) do / go",
      "C": "can get / are getting\nC) are / are going",
      "D": "got / get\nD) can / can go\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPast Simple ( Regular / Irregular Verbs ) Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "got / get\nD) can / can go\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/past-simple-regular-irregular-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPast Simple ( Regular / Irregular Verbs ) Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
  },
  {
    "id": "d31ecd9d-6ecc-4440-b8c7-4276e5c32919",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: They aren't at home. They __________ out. 8. He __________ off fora tour in Europe two weeks ago\nand he __________ three countries so far.\nB: OK. Can you give them this envelope?",
    "options": {
      "A": "set / visited\nA: Sure.",
      "B": "sets / can visit",
      "C": "is setting / visits\nA) are going",
      "D": "set / has visited\nB) go\nC) can go 9. Nancy __________ the floor, so be careful. It __________\nslippery at the moment.\nD) have gone"
    },
    "answer": "set / has visited\nB) go\nC) can go 9. Nancy __________ the floor, so be careful. It __________\nslippery at the moment.\nD) have gone"
  },
  {
    "id": "f1569cef-1e52-4458-a63f-65c8dd6ac52c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "William __________ a lot about 19th-century poets",
    "options": {
      "A": "is polishing / was\nrecently, and he __________ another book about them",
      "B": "polished / has been\na few hours ago.",
      "C": "has polished / is\nA) is reading / has bought",
      "D": "polishes / were\nB) read / can buy 10.The couple __________ to Hawaii for their honeymoon\nC) has read / bought yesterday, but they have __________ got bored there.\nD) had read / bought\nA) have gone / recently"
    },
    "answer": "has polished / is\nA) is reading / has bought"
  },
  {
    "id": "64521aff-9081-4ee2-b84a-a09c0250f88b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "__________ you __________ your homework yet ?\nB) went / already\nC) were going / just",
    "options": {
      "A": "Do / do\nD) are going / yet",
      "B": "Did / do",
      "C": "Can / do 11.A: Why are you breathing heavily?",
      "D": "Have / done\nB: I __________ the attic for hours. I am exhausted."
    },
    "answer": "Have / done\nB: I __________ the attic for hours. I am exhausted."
  },
  {
    "id": "e943104b-c1b7-4475-be19-9c6c1fac4da1",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "The boy __________ all the questions in the test\ncorrectly yesterday.",
    "options": {
      "A": "have cleaned",
      "B": "clean\nA) answered",
      "C": "am cleaning\nB) has answered",
      "D": "can clean\nC) is answering"
    },
    "answer": "have cleaned"
  },
  {
    "id": "935c4610-ac85-4f38-8bc9-03c9926c2eb5",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Hawk hasn't slept well __________ so he __________\nD) can answer\ntired at work for days.\n5. I __________ German between 2000 and 2005 when I\nwas in Turkey, but since 2008, I __________ as a sales",
    "options": {
      "A": "recently / was\nrepresentative in Germany.",
      "B": "ever / can be",
      "C": "never / is\nA) have taught / work",
      "D": "lately / has been\nB) taught / am working\nC) have taught / worked 13.Oliver __________ in Turkey and Greece in the past,\nbut surprisingly, he has __________ eaten calamari.\nD) taught / have worked"
    },
    "answer": "lately / has been\nB) taught / am working\nC) have taught / worked 13.Oliver __________ in Turkey and Greece in the past,\nbut surprisingly, he has __________ eaten calamari.\nD) taught / have worked"
  },
  {
    "id": "bd493435-d861-4389-a1e8-6d0fda0f5420",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Raphael __________ a student at university for eight",
    "options": {
      "A": "has lived / up to now\nyears. He __________ school yet.",
      "B": "lived / ever",
      "C": "has lived / already\nA) has been / hasn't finished",
      "D": "lived / never\nB) is / didn't finish\nC) was / doesn't finish 14.A: Have you __________ ridden a horse ?\nD) can be / isn't finishing\nB:No, I have __________ ridden one."
    },
    "answer": "has lived / up to now\nyears. He __________ school yet."
  },
  {
    "id": "1a5adaa8-dd83-4ed6-8df7-f52bbb041447",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "In the morning, she __________ a cake for her friend's\nbirthday and __________ it with chocolate drops.",
    "options": {
      "A": "so far / yet",
      "B": "already / since\nA) is making / is decorating",
      "C": "ever / never\nB) made / decorated",
      "D": "lately / up to now\nC) has made / has decorated\nD) can make / can decorate\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPresent Perfect Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "already / since\nA) is making / is decorating"
  },
  {
    "id": "0bdd08b8-d471-4b76-9b6d-974f4413ad2a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: __________ has he been a teacher? 18.Jean __________ of that band so far, but he __________\nthe lead singer. They were in the same school.\nB: __________ 2005.",
    "options": {
      "A": "hasn't heard / knows\nA) How long / For",
      "B": "didn't hear / knew\nB) How much / Since",
      "C": "isn't hearing / is knowing\nC) How long / Since",
      "D": "doesn't hear / can know\nD) How much / For"
    },
    "answer": "isn't hearing / is knowing\nC) How long / Since"
  },
  {
    "id": "83bdcf91-1013-4f9b-a76f-d2f7ce100e86",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: __________ have you lived here?\n16.The woman has __________ washed her hair, and now\nshe __________ it. B: __________ a very long time and I'm very happy\nhere.",
    "options": {
      "A": "ever / has dried\nA) How much / Since",
      "B": "already / dry\nB) How long / For",
      "C": "yet / dried\nC) How long / Since",
      "D": "just / is drying\nD) How much / For"
    },
    "answer": "already / dry\nB) How long / For"
  },
  {
    "id": "afc3b741-20c1-4de6-a01b-28fb0acf4430",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "456_present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "She has written five novels __________ and she has\npublished a science fiction story in a literary 20.Sue __________ a receptionist for twenty years and\nmagazine __________. she __________ to work in hotels when she finished\nschool.",
    "options": {
      "A": "recently / just\nA) can be / is starting",
      "B": "already / never\nB) was / has started",
      "C": "up to now / recently\nC) is / can start",
      "D": "so far / for\nD) has been / started\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/present-perfect-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPresent Perfect Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "up to now / recently\nC) is / can start"
  },
  {
    "id": "b93a3a7f-f604-46f2-a9e5-c47865d8032d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: When is his birthday? 8. The man is sitting at his desk _____ the middle of the\nroom and a light bulb is hanging _____ his head.\nB: It's _____ January 19tlh.",
    "options": {
      "A": "onto / under\nA) in",
      "B": "in / over\nB) on",
      "C": "on / through\nC) at",
      "D": "by / across\nD) up"
    },
    "answer": "in / over\nB) on"
  },
  {
    "id": "2a097973-a38e-40bc-b423-cab84be3f67f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Stacy travelled _____ one continent to another _____\n2. Look at the helicopter _____ the air! It is pink! bicycle last year.",
    "options": {
      "A": "in A) into / along",
      "B": "up B) out of / onto",
      "C": "on C) from / by",
      "D": "at D) up / down"
    },
    "answer": "on C) from / by"
  },
  {
    "id": "5c83a2cb-4f79-42b1-a4ef-ca30c529902f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Sally met John _____ the new cinema in Brooklyn, not 10.I am travelling to India _____ two weeks and I am\n_____ Ivy Street. going to stay there _____ the winter, too.",
    "options": {
      "A": "on / in A) on / at",
      "B": "in / at B) in / in",
      "C": "at / on C) at / in",
      "D": "near / through D) next to / on"
    },
    "answer": "at / on C) at / in"
  },
  {
    "id": "8a005755-c345-404c-b0b1-04a5160fdf09",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Marcy usually worked _____ the weekend _____ the 11.A: Where is the vacuum cleaner? I can't find it.\npast.\nB: It is _____ the door, but you need to take it _____ its",
    "options": {
      "A": "at / in box.",
      "B": "on / from\nA) behind / out of",
      "C": "in / between\nB) on / through",
      "D": "from / to\nC) next to / along"
    },
    "answer": "at / in box."
  },
  {
    "id": "d651db82-51f5-4ed0-93c6-4be39c2f5b65",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I was _____ Paris for a business trip _____ Christmas.\nD) besides / across",
    "options": {
      "A": "on / to 12.The cock jumped _____ the fence _____ the farm and\nbegan crowing.",
      "B": "at / in",
      "C": "in / at\nA) across / up",
      "D": "from / on\nB) along / down"
    },
    "answer": "in / at\nA) across / up"
  },
  {
    "id": "56c01fdc-47ac-4470-ba87-49854d0c5574",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Ryan often goes to bed _____ midnight _____ Sundays. C) among / over\nD) onto / around",
    "options": {
      "A": "between / near 13.Eric visited his aunt at the hospital _____ the morning\nand called one of his neighbours _____ noon.",
      "B": "on / in",
      "C": "in / at\nA) in / at",
      "D": "at / on\nB) on / in"
    },
    "answer": "at / on\nB) on / in"
  },
  {
    "id": "cba8315b-4d56-4220-a273-1f316ffd640a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Nelson always sits _____ Margaret in the classroom, C) at / on\nand their desk is _____ Clara and Mandy's.\nD) in / on",
    "options": {
      "A": "next to / behind 14.A: Some Indians have a red mark _____ their two\neyebrows.",
      "B": "among / near",
      "C": "across / between B: Yes, it is called a ''bindi''.",
      "D": "behind / along\nA) through\nB) onto\nC) from\nD) between\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPrepositions Of Time & Place & Movement Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "next to / behind 14.A: Some Indians have a red mark _____ their two\neyebrows."
  },
  {
    "id": "3e1e5763-5993-471d-9bdd-f87174051e6e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "In the Arabic love story, Layla and Majnun, Majnun 18.He first walked _____ the street when the traffic light\nwalks _____ the desert to find Layla. turned green and then started to walk _____ the\npavement.",
    "options": {
      "A": "through\nA) across / along",
      "B": "onto\nB) onto / through",
      "C": "across\nC) over / down",
      "D": "over\nD) around / out of"
    },
    "answer": "across\nC) over / down"
  },
  {
    "id": "b0519889-cac1-4985-9e69-20eebf1ba279",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Her grand grandfather wrote a special dictionary\n_____ the 20th century and you can find it in some 19.A: When did your cousins visit you?\nlibraries _____ present.\nB: _____ Christmas Day _____ dawn.",
    "options": {
      "A": "at / on\nA) In / on",
      "B": "on / in\nB) On / at",
      "C": "in / at\nC) At / in",
      "D": "from / near\nD) From / to"
    },
    "answer": "in / at\nC) At / in"
  },
  {
    "id": "a94c49ed-5b92-4ccd-a3a9-c55dcd33cc21",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "457_prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: The black van _____ the bank transports money.\n20.A: Can you see the turtle _____ the flowers?\nB: And there is a man _____ it. He is wearing a\nuniform. It must be the driver. B: Yes, it is coming _____ its shell. It is not afraid of\nus!",
    "options": {
      "A": "under / along\nA) at / through",
      "B": "through / near\nB) near / across",
      "C": "next to / among\nC) in / onto",
      "D": "in front of / beside\nD) among / out of\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPrepositions Of Time & Place & Movement Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "in front of / beside\nD) among / out of\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/prepositions-of-time-place-movement-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nPrepositions Of Time & Place & Movement Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
  },
  {
    "id": "c1cd2d8c-f04e-4e1c-a956-9cc563f4d9d8",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Ian _____ classes next week because he _____ to 7. A: Mum _____ the old antique table in the attic right\nanother town with the baseball team. now.",
    "options": {
      "A": "is going to attend / will travel B: Yes, she _____ it.",
      "B": "won't attend / is travelling\nA) dusts / will sell",
      "C": "isn't attending / won't travel\nB) will dust / is selling",
      "D": "will attend / will travel\nC) is dusting / is going to sell"
    },
    "answer": "won't attend / is travelling\nA) dusts / will sell"
  },
  {
    "id": "088c67ba-6b46-4c3e-bc55-037c2dc04fa3",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ their boss _____ them a pay rise?\nD) can dust / sells\nB: No, he isn't. 8. Don't come home late, or I _____ you go out with your\nfriends again.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Is / going to give\nA) am not letting",
      "B": "Will / give\nB) don't let",
      "C": "Can / give\nC) am not going to let",
      "D": "Does / give\nD) won't let"
    },
    "answer": "Is / going to give\nA) am not letting"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e0f6c78-777a-4250-af14-47e5cc5e0b5c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Who will be the winner of the next game?\n9. Save some money for the future, or you _____\nB: I think our team _____ the other team. I have difficulty when you are old.\nconfidence in them.",
    "options": {
      "A": "is going to have\nA) is defeating",
      "B": "have had\nB) won't defeat",
      "C": "will have\nC) isn't defeating",
      "D": "are having\nD) will defeat"
    },
    "answer": "are having\nD) will defeat"
  },
  {
    "id": "b1cbc986-c3c5-422f-a159-0e20a714775e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Perhaps, they _____ the museum this year.\n4. Jackie has boiled water in the pot. She _____ some tea\nand probably she _____ all of it.",
    "options": {
      "A": "open",
      "B": "are going to open\nA) is going to make / will drink",
      "C": "are opening\nB) is making / is going to drink",
      "D": "will open\nC) will make / is drinking"
    },
    "answer": "will open\nC) will make / is drinking"
  },
  {
    "id": "3caf9a92-bba1-4eb0-b892-0e311b530773",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: I _____ dieting.\nD) makes / isn't going to drink\n5. She _____ his aunt in Egypt next month. She has B: A good decision. I hope you _____ weight.\nalready organized the trip. She thinks they _____ a\ngreat time together.",
    "options": {
      "A": "will start / are losing",
      "B": "am going to start / will lose\nA) will visit / are having",
      "C": "am starting / lose\nB) has visited / are going to have",
      "D": "start / have lost\nC) is visiting / will have"
    },
    "answer": "am going to start / will lose\nA) will visit / are having"
  },
  {
    "id": "23ccdf70-6dee-4344-b29c-d4d8ed1364bd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Jessica _____ her suitcases. She is waiting out for the\nD) is going to visit / have\ntaxi now. She _____ Tom.\n6. A: Tom _____ sad.",
    "options": {
      "A": "is going to pack / will leave\nB: He _____ his office next week. That's why he is sad.",
      "B": "will pack / is going to leave",
      "C": "is packing / leaves\nA) is going to look / closes",
      "D": "has packed / is leaving\nB) will look / is going to close 13.A: I _____ here tomorrow.\nC) is looking / will close\nB: Oh, where _____ you go?\nD) looks / is closing\nA) am not going to be / do\nB) am not / did\nC) haven't been / can\nD) won't be / will\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nThe Future Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "has packed / is leaving\nB) will look / is going to close 13.A: I _____ here tomorrow.\nC) is looking / will close\nB: Oh, where _____ you go?\nD) looks / is closing\nA) am not going to be / do\nB) am not / did\nC) haven't been / can\nD) won't be / will\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nThe Future Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
  },
  {
    "id": "22546406-28a0-4fce-9f0a-59a42af4e4ba",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "It is getting cold. Come in or you _____ a cold. 18.A: Brian has bought a canvas, oil paints and brushes.\nHe _____ a portrait of his mother.",
    "options": {
      "A": "catch\nB: I believe it _____ a beautiful one.",
      "B": "wiil catch",
      "C": "are going to catch\nA) will paint / is",
      "D": "are catching\nB) is painting / has been"
    },
    "answer": "wiil catch"
  },
  {
    "id": "48876091-2416-4947-a37c-3cc66eb4f083",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I'm afraid John _____ to our wedding. He _____ to C) is going to paint / will be\nArgentina on Friday.\nD) has painted / is going to be",
    "options": {
      "A": "won't come / is flying 19.They _____ in the city centre, but they _____ to the\nsuburbs next month. They have planned everything.",
      "B": "isn't coming / flies",
      "C": "doesn't come / will fly\nA) will live / will move",
      "D": "isn't going to come / is going to fly\nB) lived / are going to move"
    },
    "answer": "won't come / is flying 19.They _____ in the city centre, but they _____ to the\nsuburbs next month. They have planned everything."
  },
  {
    "id": "a530d995-38d7-4923-9252-e06dc9531a27",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Sammy _____ that house. He _____ some money from C) are living / have moved\nthe bank for it.\nD) live / are moving",
    "options": {
      "A": "is going to buy / has already borrowed 20.It is 9 am, but dad is wearing his shorts and training\nshoes, so he _____ at the office today. Probably, he",
      "B": "will buy / always borrows\n_____ jogging in the forest.",
      "C": "bought / will probably borrow",
      "D": "is buying / is still borrowing A) isn't going to work / will go"
    },
    "answer": "is going to buy / has already borrowed 20.It is 9 am, but dad is wearing his shorts and training\nshoes, so he _____ at the office today. Probably, he"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb7dcf25-51e8-48b1-8b3d-7c2775824b76",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "458_the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I think we _____ contract tomorrow. B) isn't working / goes\nC) won't work / is going",
    "options": {
      "A": "have signed\nD) didn't work / has gone",
      "B": "are going to sign",
      "C": "are signing",
      "D": "will sign\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nThe Future Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "will sign\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/the-future-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nThe Future Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe2ee13b-2fff-46e0-8bd9-6c3d9f750999",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Bob is 79. Valerie is 79, too, so she is _____ Bob. 7. A: Caroline's guitar is very _____. I liked the woodwork\non it.",
    "options": {
      "A": "the oldest\nB: And she plays it quite _____.",
      "B": "not as old as",
      "C": "older then\nA) beautifully / the best",
      "D": "as old as\nB) more beautiful / good"
    },
    "answer": "as old as\nB) more beautiful / good"
  },
  {
    "id": "83bce1b2-7561-4b6b-b247-159b74b06a86",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Of all the cities in the world, which city is _____ to C) as beautiful as / better\nthe Equator?\nD) beautiful / well\nB: Quito. It is only 15 miles to it. 8. We can win the game. They can win the game, too,\nbecause they are _____ us.",
    "options": {
      "A": "closer than\nA) strong",
      "B": "the closest\nB) as strong as",
      "C": "close\nC) stronger",
      "D": "as close as\nD) the stron"
    },
    "answer": "the closest\nB) as strong as"
  },
  {
    "id": "c3745ed8-ed44-4a00-8708-408a61fe8d62",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Don't forget to say \"please '' when you want\nsomething from someone, dear. It is _____. 9. A: The rain is _____ it was yesterday.\nB: I understand, mum. B: Yes. Thank God, we are _____ today and can stay\nhome.",
    "options": {
      "A": "politer\nA) heavier than / free",
      "B": "as polite as\nB) heavy / freely",
      "C": "not as police as\nC) as heavy as / not as freely as",
      "D": "politer than\nD) the heaviest / freer"
    },
    "answer": "politer\nA) heavier than / free"
  },
  {
    "id": "380f7ed1-e0f7-4529-a7ed-53dcf499f0cd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Alexander is 75 kilograms. Nick is 97 kilograms so\nAlexander is _____ Nick. 10.London is 45 km away from our city, but Oxford is 78\nkm away. Therefore, London is _____ to our city _____",
    "options": {
      "A": "as heavy as Oxford.",
      "B": "the heaviest\nA) not as close / as",
      "C": "not as heavy as\nB) closer / than",
      "D": "heavier than\nC) close / in"
    },
    "answer": "not as heavy as\nB) closer / than"
  },
  {
    "id": "08d9e6be-8401-4f25-93bd-e0fd138bd64b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: You look very _____ in this dress.\nD) the closest / of\nB: Thank you. You are very _____. 11.A: This pillow doesn't feel _____ at all.",
    "options": {
      "A": "the nicest / kindly B: It is an extra firm pillow. It isn't soft, but I can sleep\n_____ on it.",
      "B": "nicely / kinder",
      "C": "nicer / the kindest\nA) softer / as comfortable as",
      "D": "nice / kind\nB) softly / more comfortable"
    },
    "answer": "nice / kind\nB) softly / more comfortable"
  },
  {
    "id": "d88f9064-d9e7-4c9f-a8b8-a9af384ce99f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: He is shouting at those children _____. Do you C) as soft as / comfortable\nknow why?\nD) soft / comfortably\nB: Because they damaged his _____ car. 12.I think you can work with either of the lawyers. They\nare both successful and the first one is _____ the",
    "options": {
      "A": "angry / expensive other.",
      "B": "as angry as / expensively\nA) experienced",
      "C": "angrily / expensive\nB) as experienced as",
      "D": "more angry / as expensive as\nC) the most experienced\nD) not as experienced as\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nAdjectives / Adverbs / Comparisons Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "angrily / expensive\nB) as experienced as"
  },
  {
    "id": "ccd02b4f-0a95-4c29-9b38-8cc24abbc5e2",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: You sounded _____ on the phone this morning. Is 17._____ way to peel tomatoes is to keep them in hot\neverything OK? water for some time first.\nB: I'm not _____. Don't worry.",
    "options": {
      "A": "The easiest",
      "B": "As easily as\nA) as sad as / badly",
      "C": "As easy as\nB) sadly / worse",
      "D": "More easily\nC) sad / bad"
    },
    "answer": "As easy as\nB) sadly / worse"
  },
  {
    "id": "579512e6-41d4-4954-9e62-00eb6ad55666",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Who is _____ student in your class?\nD) the saddest / as bad as\n14.I think your friend is _____ girl in this beauty contest. B: Aaron. Everyone is _____ him.\nI'm sure she will be the new queen.",
    "options": {
      "A": "taller / not as short as\nA) more beautiful than",
      "B": "tall / as short as\nB) the most beautiful",
      "C": "as tall as / the shortest\nC) as beautiful as",
      "D": "the tallest / shorter than\nD) not as"
    },
    "answer": "the tallest / shorter than\nD) not as"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e93ba34-c9d8-4036-bf74-8516a17d5cff",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Sally finishes this job in two hours, but Thelma\n15.Rebecca is usually _____ Beatrice because she is _____ finishes it in an hour. Definitely, Sally doesn't work\nher. She loves interacting with people. _____ Thelma.",
    "options": {
      "A": "the most friendly / the most extroverted A) as quickly as",
      "B": "as friendly as / extroverted B) more quickly",
      "C": "more friendly than / more extroverted than C) the most quickly",
      "D": "friendly / as extroverted as D) quickly"
    },
    "answer": "the most friendly / the most extroverted A) as quickly as"
  },
  {
    "id": "2da7e46b-9053-442b-bbe1-3b9bdb0cb640",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "459_adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Edgar is _____ at tennis _____ his sister because he 20.Jazz music is not _____ in Turkey _____ pop music, but\nhas practised a lot, too. still, you can go to many jazz festivals here.",
    "options": {
      "A": "as good / as A) more popularly / than",
      "B": "the best / of B) as popular / as",
      "C": "as well / as C) more popular / as",
      "D": "good / than D) as popularly / as\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/adjectives-adverbs-comparisons-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nAdjectives / Adverbs / Comparisons Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "as good / as A) more popularly / than"
  },
  {
    "id": "7140c1b7-b0a5-45a9-af3a-686ee53f75be",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ can solve this problem? 8. A: _____?\nB: Bob. B: He sent them to Susie.",
    "options": {
      "A": "What A) Who sent the flowers",
      "B": "How B) Who did he send the flowers to",
      "C": "Which C) What did he send to Susie",
      "D": "Who D) Where did he send the flowers"
    },
    "answer": "Who D) Where did he send the flowers"
  },
  {
    "id": "2261a190-377d-4935-b8f5-5c24f12d4cdf",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____? 9. A: You are a nurse, _____?\nB: Yes, I am. B: I am. Please, don't disturb me now, _____?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Do you have breakfast A) are you / shall we",
      "B": "Are you going to have breakfast B) aren't I / won't you",
      "C": "Have you had breakfast C) aren't you / will you",
      "D": "Am I having breakfast D) am I / do you"
    },
    "answer": "Are you going to have breakfast B) aren't I / won't you"
  },
  {
    "id": "d03ed52e-b292-4135-8a68-f45f10bd6a03",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ 10.A: _____?\nB: No, I haven't. B: No, you haven't.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Have I given you my number? A) Have I given you my number",
      "B": "Do you have a tape recorder? B) Do you have a tape recorder",
      "C": "Have you got a pair of scissors? C) Have you got a pair of scissors",
      "D": "Did you give a party last night? D) Did you give a party last night"
    },
    "answer": "Have you got a pair of scissors? C) Have you got a pair of scissors"
  },
  {
    "id": "71008708-ec00-45f5-85e9-3a01a1c031a6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "The little girl can hear us, _____? 11.A: _____?",
    "options": {
      "A": "can she B: Mexico.",
      "B": "can we\nA) Is he from Peru or Mexico",
      "C": "can't she\nB) Have you ever visited Mexico",
      "D": "can't we\nC) Do you like Mexican food"
    },
    "answer": "can't she\nB) Have you ever visited Mexico"
  },
  {
    "id": "0988f1d6-5aea-437c-b44e-7366697d1eb7",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ glass is this?\nD) Will you go to Mexico this year\nB: It's Brad's. 12.Henry has never left his hometown, _____?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Who A) hasn't it",
      "B": "Which B) has he",
      "C": "Whose C) has it",
      "D": "How D) hasn't he"
    },
    "answer": "Whose C) has it"
  },
  {
    "id": "c846d489-96dd-4ac3-94ed-aefa8ede5796",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ emails have we received from customers? 13.This is a good film, _____?\nB: Fifty-nine.",
    "options": {
      "A": "is it",
      "B": "isn't this\nA) How many",
      "C": "is this\nB) How much",
      "D": "isn't it\nC) How often"
    },
    "answer": "is it"
  },
  {
    "id": "5244bc0e-4480-4fdc-8513-fe5e29e84a12",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Let's eat out tonight, _____?\nD) How long\n7. A: _____ B: You got your paycheque today, _____?\nB: Joey cut the paper. A: You are right.",
    "options": {
      "A": "What will Joey do? A) shall we / didn't you",
      "B": "Is joey cutting the paper? B) won't we / did you",
      "C": "Who cut the paper? C) shall we / do you",
      "D": "Why did Joey cut the paper? D) will we / aren't you\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nQuestions Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "What will Joey do? A) shall we / didn't you"
  },
  {
    "id": "c5dc8d5e-ae6f-45c8-a8a8-b99d7cf16b30",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "15. A: _____? 18.A: _____ have you been here?\nB: No, I don't. B: For an hour.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Have I given you my number A: You are waiting for someone, _____?",
      "B": "Do you have a tape recorder\nB: No, I'm not.",
      "C": "Have you got a pair of scissors",
      "D": "Did you give a party last night A) How many / am I"
    },
    "answer": "Do you have a tape recorder\nB: No, I'm not."
  },
  {
    "id": "904a9437-3c92-47d9-a2ad-0bc8710e3eb3",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ caused the accident? B) How often / are you\nC) How long / aren't you\nB: I don't know. It wasn't serious, _____?\nD) How much / aren't I",
    "options": {
      "A": "Which / wasn't it 19.A: There is a new play at the theatre, _____?",
      "B": "What / was it\nB: Yes, there is. You want to see it, _____?",
      "C": "How / wasn't there",
      "D": "Who / wasn't this A) is there / isn't it"
    },
    "answer": "What / was it\nB: Yes, there is. You want to see it, _____?"
  },
  {
    "id": "30e9b16a-71cb-4c5d-a8c5-f97defa50db8",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "460_questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ did you see your dietician last summer? B) isn't this / do you\nC) is it / aren't you\nB: Only twice.\nD) isn't there / don't you",
    "options": {
      "A": "How many 20.A: Don't be late for dinner, _____?",
      "B": "How old\nB: OK. I will be home before 5. We have guests,",
      "C": "How often _____?",
      "D": "How much\nA) do you / have we\nB) will you / don't we\nC) don't you / do we\nD) won't you / haven't we\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/questions-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nQuestions Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "How often _____?"
  },
  {
    "id": "6ffc1fd7-e09e-4478-b17f-7569bf7a49bb",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: You are ill. You _____ in the balcony. It isn't warm 7. Margaret _____ speak Italian and English, so she _____\noutside. work with a translator in this project.\nB: I'm wearing warm clothes. Don't worry.",
    "options": {
      "A": "needn't / mustn't",
      "B": "can't / couldn't\nA) needn't sit",
      "C": "can / needn't\nB) can sit",
      "D": "must / musn't\nC) must sit"
    },
    "answer": "must / musn't\nC) must sit"
  },
  {
    "id": "de77ff97-9258-4ae2-b83e-a93d485aa95b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: I _____ open this jar.\nD) mustn't sit\n2. A: I don't want to leave my phone at the desk before I B: Let me help you. _____ use a knife?\nenter the exam hall. _____?\nA: No problem.\nB: Unfortunately, yes. It is the rule.",
    "options": {
      "A": "can't / Can I\nA) Can I",
      "B": "mustn't / Must I\nB) Must I",
      "C": "needn't / May I\nC) May I",
      "D": "can / Could I\nD) Could I"
    },
    "answer": "can't / Can I\nA) Can I"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6d5cb7a-3dd3-4137-8b8b-5033b1df8356",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ turn on the volume of the radio? This is my\n3. A: You _____ wash those strawberries. I've already favourite song.\nwashed them.\nB: Sure. You _____ ask me. I'm never disturbed by the\nB: Oh, good. Thank you. music.",
    "options": {
      "A": "needn't A) May I / can't",
      "B": "must B) Could I / must",
      "C": "couldn't C) Must I / could",
      "D": "can D) Can I / needn't"
    },
    "answer": "can D) Can I / needn't"
  },
  {
    "id": "ed916e36-6995-43c2-97c1-a5bde58972cd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I _____ tell the time when I was 8 years old, but now I 10.A: _____ ask you a question?\ncan.\nB: Yes, sure, but I _____ answer it if it is about my",
    "options": {
      "A": "can private life.",
      "B": "couldn't\nA) Do I / needn't",
      "C": "can't\nB) Can I / couldn't",
      "D": "could\nC) May I / can't"
    },
    "answer": "couldn't\nA) Do I / needn't"
  },
  {
    "id": "cd3bbe48-f19c-4518-8fc4-31ab5238c695",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ help you?\nD) Did I / could\nB: Yes, please. I'm looking for a leather jacket. 11.A: I _____ work hard during the weekend.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Must I B: Why?",
      "B": "Have I\nA: I _____ finish my weekly task yesterday.",
      "C": "Can I",
      "D": "Did I A) can / mustn't"
    },
    "answer": "Can I"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d51c877-2935-4c8d-8b95-9be2a4c32f74",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Betty _____ pay her rent today. B) mustn't / must\nC) can't / needn't\nB: I hope she has enough money.\nD) must / couldn't",
    "options": {
      "A": "can 12.She _____ smoke because she is pregnant and it is\nharmful to the baby.",
      "B": "must",
      "C": "needn't\nA) needn't",
      "D": "can't\nB) couldn't\nC) mustn't\nD) can\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nModal Verbs Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "must"
  },
  {
    "id": "31a767ed-bbbd-43ab-9958-6e638bcf6ea0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I _____ get a visa to go to England. I'm a citizen of 17.You _____ give up. You are strong enough to overcome\nEngland. this problem.",
    "options": {
      "A": "couldn't A) mustn't",
      "B": "mustn't B) needn't",
      "C": "can't C) must",
      "D": "needn't D) can"
    },
    "answer": "needn't D) can"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb6fd753-3e70-435d-b1b8-9fee2865550e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ read and write when you were 5? 18.A: Jeremy _____ come to the dinner party today.\nB: No, I _____. B: I know. As far as I know, he _____ go on a business\ntrip.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Could you / couldn't\nA) can / hasn't",
      "B": "Can you / can't\nB) needn't / mustn't",
      "C": "May I / must\nC) can't / must",
      "D": "Must I / needn't\nD) mustn't / has"
    },
    "answer": "Could you / couldn't\nA) can / hasn't"
  },
  {
    "id": "00d4b619-00cc-431b-a34d-05bc20846637",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: _____ pay any money for this treatment?\n19.A: I _____ speak English fluently before I stayed in\nB: No, you _____. England for a year.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Can I / didn't B: But now you _____. That's very good.",
      "B": "Must I / needn't\nA) could / could",
      "C": "May I / must\nB) must / needn't",
      "D": "Could I / do\nC) couldn't / can"
    },
    "answer": "Must I / needn't\nA) could / could"
  },
  {
    "id": "988029c8-13ae-4821-bb23-a5299d1b320e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "461_modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "This medicine _____ heal you. Give it a try.\nD) mustn't / must",
    "options": {
      "A": "can 20.A: _____ see your passport?",
      "B": "needn't\nB: Why _____ show it?",
      "C": "mustn't",
      "D": "couldn't A: Because I need to see a picture ID.\nA) Could I / may I\nB) May I / could I\nC) Must I / can I\nD) Can I / must I\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/modal-verbs-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nModal Verbs Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "can 20.A: _____ see your passport?"
  },
  {
    "id": "f062268e-dd77-4e9d-89f6-8e4f35f4b31d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: I want _____ something to you. 7. Mary asked us how _____ after that plant and we\nsuggested _____ some research on the Internet.\nB: Let me _____. You lost my book. didn't you?",
    "options": {
      "A": "to look / to do\nA: Yes. How do you know it?",
      "B": "looking / do\nB: Somebody brought it back to me.",
      "C": "look / to do",
      "D": "to look / doing\nA) telling / to guess"
    },
    "answer": "look / to do"
  },
  {
    "id": "ddac5535-30d2-45cb-8856-500f7ad8a80f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Jane is bad at _____. I think Joe should type our\nB) tell / guessing group assignment. He is fast.\nC) to tell / guess\nB: We can't make him _____ it because he said before\nD) tell / to guess\nhe wouldn't do it.\n2. A: How did he manage _____ the prison?",
    "options": {
      "A": "typing / do\nB: I don't know, but obviously he really hated _____",
      "B": "to type / doing\nthere.",
      "C": "type / to do\nA) to escape / be",
      "D": "typing / doing\nB) escape / to be 9. Let's continue _____. We are almost there. Would you\nC) escaping / be like _____ some water?\nD) to escape / being\nA) walking / drink"
    },
    "answer": "typing / do\nB: I don't know, but obviously he really hated _____"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2ed0f48-0aa8-4fe2-b4b5-68495a288c87",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: You have promised _____ here on time, but you are\nB) to walk / drinking\nlate again.\nC) walk / to drink\nB: Sorry. I tried _____ even earlier, but there was too D) walking / to drink\nmuch traffic.\n10.A: Have you finished _____ your room?",
    "options": {
      "A": "to be / to arrive\nB: Yes. I tidied it early in the morning _____ more time",
      "B": "be / arriving for my studies.",
      "C": "being / arrive\nA) to tidy / to having",
      "D": "to be / arrive\nB) tidying / to have"
    },
    "answer": "to be / to arrive\nB: Yes. I tidied it early in the morning _____ more time"
  },
  {
    "id": "92db544a-e0c8-4d3a-b8ed-826e42de7632",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: They offered _____ the machine for 2000 $. What\ndo you think? C) tidy / have\nD) to tidy / having\nB: I prefer _____ a brand new one.\n11.A: We will go _____ tomorrow morning. Would you like\n_____ with us?",
    "options": {
      "A": "selling / buy",
      "B": "to sell / buying B: Thank you, but I want to sleep until late tomorrow.",
      "C": "sell / to buy\nA) jogging / to come",
      "D": "selling / buying\nB) to jog / coming"
    },
    "answer": "to sell / buying B: Thank you, but I want to sleep until late tomorrow."
  },
  {
    "id": "d9c3528c-d101-4112-aa78-397b1b379b76",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Sally stopped _____ to the gym.\nC) jog / come\nB: I thought she enjoyed _____ time there. D) jogging / coming\n12.He dislikes _____ colourful clothes. Nobody can make",
    "options": {
      "A": "going / spending\nhim _____ even a simple green pullover. He always",
      "B": "to go / spend wears black.",
      "C": "go / to spend\nA) wear / to wear",
      "D": "going / spend\nB) to wear / wearing"
    },
    "answer": "going / spending\nhim _____ even a simple green pullover. He always"
  },
  {
    "id": "c11594ef-6913-4cfe-9538-f7d7eb2c0f25",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Bob is too inexperienced _____ that Job.\nC) wearing / wear\nB: But he still hopes _____ it. D) wear / wearing",
    "options": {
      "A": "do / get",
      "B": "doing / getting",
      "C": "to do / to get",
      "D": "doing / get\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nInfinitive Too & Enough - Gerund Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "to do / to get"
  },
  {
    "id": "a431a9fe-70c4-489b-ad65-97cdfb92f887",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "I don't know what _____. I hate _____ to parties, but I 17.I must _____ now _____ the bus.\nmust attend this one.",
    "options": {
      "A": "go / to catch\nA) doing / go",
      "B": "to go / catch\nB) do / to go",
      "C": "going / catch\nC) to do / going",
      "D": "go / catching\nD) doing / to go"
    },
    "answer": "going / catch\nC) to do / going"
  },
  {
    "id": "ce873d6c-b861-42d4-9944-5396954878a8",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "William decided _____ the concert because he is ill,\n14.A: Are you afraid of _____ in the ocean? but he hopes _____ the concert next week.\nB: No. The water is just too cold _____ now.",
    "options": {
      "A": "cancel / to give",
      "B": "cancelling / giving\nA) swim / swimming",
      "C": "to cancel / to give\nB) to swim / swim",
      "D": "cancel / give\nC) swimming / to swim"
    },
    "answer": "to cancel / to give\nB) to swim / swim"
  },
  {
    "id": "a44d223c-26b0-4799-800a-ef7c987fbc5e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Jenny has started _____ her thesis at last.\nD) swim / swim\n15.A: What do you expect me _____ in this situation? B: Oh, good for her! I hope she manages _____ it on\ntime.\nB: Just try _____ calmer.",
    "options": {
      "A": "writing / to finish\nA) to do / be",
      "B": "write / finishing\nB) do / being",
      "C": "to write / finish\nC) doing / be",
      "D": "writing / finishing\nD) to do / to be"
    },
    "answer": "writing / to finish\nA) to do / be"
  },
  {
    "id": "33e6ff28-c3d9-4251-b2fe-b5302e068da1",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "462_infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: Michael is really keen on _____ tennis.\n16.A: Let's go _____, shall we?\nB: I know, and he expects to be good enough _____ in\nB: I'm planning _____ the rest of the day reading my national tournaments one day.\nbook here on the couch.",
    "options": {
      "A": "to play / to play\nA) skate / spending",
      "B": "play / playing\nB) skating / to spend",
      "C": "to play / play\nC) to skate / spend",
      "D": "playing / to play\nD) skate / spend\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nInfinitive Too & Enough - Gerund Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "playing / to play\nD) skate / spend\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/infinitive-too-enough-gerund-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nInfinitive Too & Enough - Gerund Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
  },
  {
    "id": "902ef98d-61f3-44ca-b772-6e5fb1522313",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Aaron and Milan are friends and _______ of them go to 8. Ryan bought two blankets yesterday and he has\nthe same school. They are classmates, too. already washed _______ them.",
    "options": {
      "A": "none A) both of",
      "B": "both B) none of",
      "C": "all C) neither",
      "D": "neither D) all"
    },
    "answer": "both B) none of"
  },
  {
    "id": "271a77bd-4b9e-44b3-9e07-f70c0813d248",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "A: There are four radios in the attic. 9. Linda will invite _______ her neighbours over for\ndinner. She thinks there will be more than fifteen\nB: Yes, but _______ of them work. They are _______ people.\nbroken.",
    "options": {
      "A": "all of\nA) neither / none",
      "B": "neither of\nB) all / both",
      "C": "both of\nC) both / neither",
      "D": "none of\nD) none /all"
    },
    "answer": "none of\nD) none /all"
  },
  {
    "id": "5af5be1c-1082-404b-bed4-33d4c01b53a2",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "He gave me two music CDs, but I liked _______ them.\n3. A: I have got two dictionaries, but _______ of them\ninclude the meaning of that word in it.",
    "options": {
      "A": "all",
      "B": "neither of\nB: You can look it up in an online dictionary then.",
      "C": "both\nA) none",
      "D": "none of\nB) both 11.A: Which of the last 2 episodes did you like?\nC) neither\nB: _______ them. I think _______ of them were very\nD) all\nboring."
    },
    "answer": "neither of\nB: You can look it up in an online dictionary then."
  },
  {
    "id": "206d579f-e545-4bc8-9793-cf8efe5f28b4",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Hans and Klaus are from Germany, and _______ them\nare from the city of Frankfurt.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Neither of / both",
      "B": "Both of / none\nA) both of",
      "C": "All / neither\nB) all",
      "D": "None / all\nC) none of"
    },
    "answer": "Neither of / both"
  },
  {
    "id": "fb57d1ec-7278-430b-ae6a-dcc7070e6c27",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Samuel bought some sweets from the shop, and he\nD) neither\nate _______ them in 2 hours.\n5. A: _______ the pancakes are burnt.",
    "options": {
      "A": "none\nB: Still, Hillary has eaten five of them.",
      "B": "both of",
      "C": "all of\nA) Both of",
      "D": "neither\nB) None of\nC) All of 13.There are two slices of cake left on the plate. I'll eat\n_______ them. You can have them.\nD) Neither of"
    },
    "answer": "all of\nA) Both of"
  },
  {
    "id": "034a8c9c-40da-45e0-9d49-597dfe6fae7c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Nancy and Jenny are 27 years old and they are",
    "options": {
      "A": "none of\n_______ bankers.",
      "B": "both",
      "C": "neither of\nA) neither of",
      "D": "all\nB) both\nC) none 14.A: Are _______ the cupboards empty?\nD) all of\nB: No, Only the one on the left is empty. There are"
    },
    "answer": "both"
  },
  {
    "id": "eef12a27-145c-4d6b-9144-42e345216e94",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "_______ the eleven footballers in the team were happy plates inside the other one.\nabout the final score _______ of them were sad.",
    "options": {
      "A": "all of\nA) None of / All",
      "B": "neither\nB) Both / None",
      "C": "both of\nC) Neither of / Both",
      "D": "none\nD) All / Neither\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nQuantifiers 2 Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "all of\nA) None of / All"
  },
  {
    "id": "fa287c8d-3e73-4112-a820-750afa42ba79",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "She has got lots of books in her bookcase, and she 18._______ the apples in the basket are rotten, so I can\nhas read _______ them. use _______ them for the pie.",
    "options": {
      "A": "all of A) Both / neither",
      "B": "both of B) All of / none of",
      "C": "none C) None of / both",
      "D": "neither D) Neither / all of"
    },
    "answer": "all of A) Both / neither"
  },
  {
    "id": "7ef6241c-dc01-4889-a024-b96db7a524c9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "Kyle has tried many shoes on for the last two hours, 19.He wrote hundreds of poems, but he published\nbut _______ of them fit him. _______ them.",
    "options": {
      "A": "all A) all",
      "B": "both B) neither of",
      "C": "none C) none of",
      "D": "neither D) both"
    },
    "answer": "none C) none of"
  },
  {
    "id": "cf58498e-4c54-489a-9d6d-58f782aa4212",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "463_quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": "A1-A2",
    "question": "_______ the paintings are exceptionally beautiful, but I 20._______ of the five girls has short black hair. _______ of\nlove _______ them. them have long brown hair.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Neither of / both of A) Neither / Both",
      "B": "Both of / none of B) All / Neither",
      "C": "All of / all C) Both / None",
      "D": "None of / neither D) None / All\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/quantifiers-2-test-a1-a2-grammar-exercises/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nQuantifiers 2 Test A1 - A2 Grammar Exercises"
    },
    "answer": "Neither of / both of A) Neither / Both"
  },
  {
    "id": "5850979e-4389-403c-954a-2328de90bdaf",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. 6. Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Last year, tens of thousands of people claimed A) A club for women = A womens' club... Toys for\nthat they had sighted a UFO in the region. children = Children's toys",
      "B": "Houses have roofs. All sorts of roof construction B) The parents of all the other boys = All the other\nare possible to the carpenter who is able and willing. boys' parents",
      "C": "These peoples are not indigenous Europeans. C) The glass of someone else = Someone else's glass\nThey are the descendants of several migrant tribes\nwho settled in these parts in the tenth century.",
      "D": "The name of my sister-in-law = My sister-in-law's\nD) A dog is good friend to a man. name\nE) I come from northern Turkland. She comes from E) The son of Pharaoh's daughter was the daughter\nthe South. This summer, I will be travelling south; of Pharaoh's son.\nand she will be travelling north. 7. Choose the odd one out."
    },
    "answer": "The name of my sister-in-law = My sister-in-law's\nD) A dog is good friend to a man. name\nE) I come from northern Turkland. She comes from E) The son of Pharaoh's daughter was the daughter\nthe South. This summer, I will be travelling south; of Pharaoh's son.\nand she will be travelling north. 7. Choose the odd one out."
  },
  {
    "id": "7f12c5a9-5f56-4f5c-a0b3-10e26595dede",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "That's too much money for a simple toy like that!\nA) I can write in ink or with a pencil.",
      "B": "The wind proved strong enough to blow the roof\nB) Fruit is very good for the brain. Apples and other off.\nfresh fruits are indispensable for your health and",
      "C": "This soup is too hot for me to drink it.\nwork wonders for your teeth.",
      "D": "I don't have enough money on me to pay the bill.\nC) Most later breeds of these sheep now give us E) He is too unpopular to win the elections.\nsome really superior quality wool. 8. Choose the odd one out.\nD) Coffee is a drink. Tea is another drink.\nE) Put a lemon in your soup instead of salt. A) You may come and see me any day, but you must\ncome some day."
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "b50ac074-487e-4bc5-a229-82381150c4d9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.\nB) \"Please give me some more.\" \"I'm sorry, but there",
    "options": {
      "A": "What a pity your friend couldn't come! isn't some left.\"",
      "B": "What thoughtless of him!",
      "C": "Didn't you do some work yesterday? I feel certain\nC) What a clever boy you are! you did.",
      "D": "Oh, God! There's no limit to how stupid one can D) You aren't expecting anyone to call, are you?\nget! E) These aren't my books. Did I take some of yours\nE) How gracefully she walks! by mistake?"
    },
    "answer": "What thoughtless of him!"
  },
  {
    "id": "1d3b45e9-42d6-45d0-8ebc-44a9e60f5275",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. 9. Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "He took up swimming as a sport last year. A) What were you two talking about out there in the",
      "B": "I should like a house in a country. garden?",
      "C": "\"May I walk you home?\" was the next question he B) Can you tell us how many of those aren't yours?\nasked. C) Who phoned this morning? You hear me? I'm",
      "D": "The bodies of most animals (all except sponges) asking you who phoned this morning.\nare made up of cells organized into tissues. D) Sergen is a great player. One never knows which\nE) I am fatuously fond of raw kangaroo meat feet he is going to kick the ball with?\nsprinkled with parmesan cheese. E) Who told you not to do it? Why should they do"
    },
    "answer": "I should like a house in a country. garden?"
  },
  {
    "id": "92dfc4bf-39d7-4422-a3bf-5bd041bd6119",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "560_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. such a thing?\n10.Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Just between you and me, it's her I'm afraid of, not\nhim. A) He is much less cooperative than we had",
      "B": "Do you really believe him -- now that you know he expected he would be.\nis the root cause of all that trouble -- is more suitable B) She's not so ugly as you said she was.\nfor the job than I am?",
      "C": "She is so stupid as I thought she would be.\nC) What! Me accept a present from him! I never even",
      "D": "You'd be less well-off if you were married and had\nspeak to him! children.\nD) Surely, it's him you mean, not me! E) It is safer to tease a lion than scorn a woman.\nE) I think you're far prettier than them all.\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-1/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nGrammar and Structure Revision MCQ Test With Answers - Odd One Out\nExercise 1"
    },
    "answer": "Do you really believe him -- now that you know he expected he would be.\nis the root cause of all that trouble -- is more suitable B) She's not so ugly as you said she was.\nfor the job than I am?"
  },
  {
    "id": "3cdd1986-1066-4b4a-8b8e-8ec6c3856e7e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. 6. Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "I had my car repaired for me yesterday. A) What have you been doing while I've been out?",
      "B": "We don't have them cleaned very often. B) Have you ever been beyond Erzurum?",
      "C": "Have someone bring it to you on a tray. C) What good films have you seen during this past",
      "D": "Why don't you have it brought to you on a tray? fortnight?\nE) Will you have it seen to soon? D) How long have you been seeing him again?"
    },
    "answer": "I had my car repaired for me yesterday. A) What have you been doing while I've been out?"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b9d99b1-4e2e-48f7-b7ac-45df76baf6bd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. E) You have been smoking at least five cigarettes\nsince you came.",
    "options": {
      "A": "All junior officers are to report to the Colonel at\n7. Choose the odd one out.\nonce.",
      "B": "I thought you were supposed to go and see your A) I generally do wear a hat in winter.\nboss this afternoon. B) I nearly always have to do it myself.",
      "C": "Do I have to show my pass every time I go in? C) I have seen rarely a worse piece of workmanship.",
      "D": "You've got to give it back to me before you leave. D) He always does say rude things like that.\nE) No, you haven't to salute him every time you see E) He only lent it to me.\nhim. 8. Choose the odd one out."
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "259cc019-7b42-4bca-9a2e-4eb046db488f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "As he was madly dashing down the steps, he\nA) You needn't have bought one of these; we really suddenly slipped on a banana peel and came\nneed one. tumbling down.",
      "B": "They didn't need to push it into the corner, B) When we were living in that house we had three\nbecause it was there already. servants.",
      "C": "You needn't have said anything; if you hadn't, he C) We went fishing everyday when we were in Göcek.\nwould never have known about it.",
      "D": "You needn't have brought any food; but since you D) When the war broke out, we lived in Mersin.\nhave, let's eat it now. E) You were wearing a new hat when I met you\nE) We didn't need to spend any money at all, which yesterday.\nwas a great relief for us all. 9. Choose the odd one out."
    },
    "answer": "As he was madly dashing down the steps, he\nA) You needn't have bought one of these; we really suddenly slipped on a banana peel and came\nneed one. tumbling down."
  },
  {
    "id": "613ef4f9-8b79-4727-b253-2ba2c7ac3ebf",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "You'll have noticed from my lecture how\nA) The maids used to wash the floors once a week. complicated this subject really is.",
      "B": "Once the floors were washed by the maids for a B) I take it that this is the right way of doing it.\nwhole week.",
      "C": "Am I supposed to think that this'll be the very last\nC) There used to be a separate washing day for the time?\nfloors.",
      "D": "I shall have done a lot of work while he will be\nD) The maids refused to wash the floors twice a asleep\nweek. E) I take it for granted that you'll finish the job on\nE) The floors were used to being washed once a time.\nweek. 10.Choose the odd one out."
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "75ed87c4-ce08-4903-a0a3-c3a21690eb47",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "561_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "The valley had been flooded a year ago and it still\nA) \"He wasn't late last night.\" \"No, he wasn't, was showed some signs of it.\nhe?\"",
      "B": "I felt certain that they were going to ask me what\nB) They don't understand what we are saying, do had happened to their friend.\nthey?",
      "C": "She was wondering why I hadn't visited her\nC) There never was any talk of it, was there? before?",
      "D": "\"You're rather late.\" \"Yes, I am a bit, aren't I?\" D) It was an ex-convict who had done the killing.\nE) Doing all these exercises will do you a lot of good, E) He jumped up as if he'd been stung.\nwon't they?\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-2/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nGrammar and Structure Revision MCQ Test With Answers - Odd One Out\nExercise 2"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "2534e51f-d402-4ff3-aa95-8ca23a79e0f3",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. 6. Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "If it were thirsty, it would show some signs of it, A) Wouldn't you rather have something else instead.\nwouldn't it?",
      "B": "I wonder whose else would do instead.\nB) You won't learn to speak Turkish properly unless",
      "C": "How else could it possibly be mended?\nyou don't come here and stay with us for a couple of",
      "D": "Couldn't it be someone else's? All mine are here,\nmonths. safe and sound.\nC) If you go downtown, will you buy a few things for E) Isn't there anyone else time you can waste instead\nme? of mine?\nD) If it's convenient for you, let's meet at nine. 7. Choose the odd one out.\nE) I shan't write to him unless he writes to me.\nA) He was very sorry to hear of your disappointment."
    },
    "answer": "I wonder whose else would do instead.\nB) You won't learn to speak Turkish properly unless"
  },
  {
    "id": "70373bb2-8d15-45ee-ac14-187f09fd4df0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "A person who refused to eat would be dead within",
      "B": "She hopes to know by tomorrow.\ntwo or three months.",
      "C": "I object to being pushed around.\nB) What's the matter? You look as if you could do",
      "D": "I'm looking forward to see you tomorrow.\nwith a drink. E) She was told not to come here ever again.\nC) Suppose he asked me for the money tomorrow! 8. Choose the odd one out.\nD) I feel as if my head were on fire.\nE) I wish I didn't break it. But since I have, I will pay A) She is happy to have found such a nice place to\nfor it. live in.\nB) The last person to address me like that was in"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "3338bc52-49a0-4697-80cf-ed18bf3de4fb",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.\nhospital for a whole week.",
    "options": {
      "A": "You'd rather she didn't say anything, wouldn't C) I surprised to hear such words from you.\nyou? D) We are supposed to be leaving this evening.",
      "B": "He has his breakfast at eight, doesn't he? E) She was afraid to go past the haunted house on",
      "C": "He couldn't have arrived before the others, could her own.\nhe have? 9. Choose the odd one out.",
      "D": "I suppose he ought to have known that, oughtn't\nhe? A) I don't like having to do any homework.\nE) Let's pretend we're not here, shall we? B) It's no use asking him to lend you the money.\nC) I hate practising reading aloud without having"
    },
    "answer": "He couldn't have arrived before the others, could her own.\nhe have? 9. Choose the odd one out."
  },
  {
    "id": "074b2235-fe6a-408c-ab0b-93e69658e472",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.\nlearnt the new words first.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Let me read it for you, will you? D) I'm considering giving up smoking one of these",
      "B": "\"I feel very sorry for you!\" \"Oh, you do, don't days.\nyou?\" E) It's a good thing that it has stopped to rain.",
      "C": "\"I'd go quite mad if I had to live with you!\" \"Oh, 10.Choose the odd one out.\nyou would, would you?\"",
      "D": "I say, come and see me tomorrow. Now, will you A) Do you know how to make Turkish coffee?\nor will you not? B) A lawyer advised me what to do.\nE) \"No, I won't listen to you!\" \"Oh, you won't, won't C) I can't imagine why are you so angry with me.\nyou?\" D) We just don't know what to open it with.\nE) My friend couldn't remember where to go."
    },
    "answer": "\"I feel very sorry for you!\" \"Oh, you do, don't days.\nyou?\" E) It's a good thing that it has stopped to rain."
  },
  {
    "id": "9d4018cb-c950-451b-9232-4eba0c2f4844",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "562_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "\"Have you got the tickets?\" \"Yes, I've got.\"",
      "B": "Haven't they got anything better to do?",
      "C": "She got bitten by a stray dog",
      "D": "Haven't you got any cigarettes? Here. Have one of\nmine.\nE) Have you got to go back tonight?\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-3/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nGrammar and Structure Revision MCQ Test With Answers - Odd One Out\nExercise 3"
    },
    "answer": "\"Have you got the tickets?\" \"Yes, I've got.\""
  },
  {
    "id": "f630dc5a-c5e4-4f06-aab4-8b01391926ae",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. 5. Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Although you think you understand how to do A) The journey, as I recall it, was long and tedious.\nsomething at the time, you may later find out that",
      "B": "We were at a disadvantage in that they\nyou misunderstood it all or cannot remember how to outnumbered us two to one.\ndo just one of the steps.",
      "C": "You may do it whichever way you choose to.\nB) Has anyone got an idea who she is speaking to?",
      "D": "Your friend climbs trees as a monkey.\nC) A lawyer advised me not to do. E) This time, he didn't fail to respond the way we\nD) I wish I knew what the world is coming to. wanted him to.\nE) I'm beginning to get really cross now. Don't you 6. Choose the odd one out.\nknow who you're talking to?\nA) Ironically, bad as things are, we know that"
    },
    "answer": "You may do it whichever way you choose to.\nB) Has anyone got an idea who she is speaking to?"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ab56d24-46af-405b-909d-a5bb30879e14",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.\neverything could be worse and that we can only be",
    "options": {
      "A": "Whoever says that is a liar. thankful they aren't worse than they are.",
      "B": "I will follow you / Follow you wherever you may go B) Being a mother herself, she'll understand your\n/ There isn't an ocean too deep / A mountain so high predicament.\nit can keep / Keep me away, away from my love...",
      "C": "No matter how bad things are, because we had\nC) Whenever I want some company / Whenever I never given up hope completely.\nneed a song to play / Whenever my love is sitting by",
      "D": "Things being as they are, unfortunately the\nme / And when I can't find the words to say / I let the economy shows no signs of an early recovery.\ndrums do the talking... E) However rich some people are, they never seem\nD) We were warmly welcomed wherever we went.We to be satisfied with their lot.\nwere warmly welcomed wherever we went. 7. Choose the odd one out.\nE) Eat whatever you like it.\nA) The person whom I am going to talk about now is"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "6f0f2a02-b8ca-4f23-a4f2-de1fd91a42c0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.\nsomebody you all know.",
    "options": {
      "A": "You can stay here, as long as you are quite.",
      "B": "The person who I am going to talk about him now\nB) \"Has she ever stayed here before?\" \"Not that I is somebody you all know.\nknow of.\"",
      "C": "The person I am going to talk about now is\nC) You can have the lot, for all I care. somebody you all know.",
      "D": "Yes, he may bring along a friend, as far as I'm D) The person that I am going to talk about now is\nconcerned. somebody, I am sure, you all know.\nE) \"Have you ever had any kidney trouble?\" \"Not that E) The person I am going to talk about now is\nI know of.\" somebody, I am sure, you all know."
    },
    "answer": "You can stay here, as long as you are quite."
  },
  {
    "id": "44c3ec13-55cd-45b1-946e-efbcda860428",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out. 8. Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "I can't come with you, because I haven't got a A) They were wondering about what it was that the\nticket. man wanted.",
      "B": "Since we're early, let's have a drink first. B) The switchboard is to be manned at all times.",
      "C": "As you've been here before, you'd better lead the C) It's time you buy yourself a new pair of shoes.\nway.",
      "D": "I suggest that each team be given equal points.\nD) Some major investment projects have been E) \"Let's take a taxi, shall we?\" \"Yes, let's.\"\nsuspended in view of the fact that the country is 9. Choose the odd one out.\ncurrently running a large budget deficit.\nE) For it's nearly bedtime, we must finish the game A) Weren't you told to be here by six?\nsoon. B) The orchestra is said to have played that piece\nbeautifully.\nC) This matter must certainly be looked into.\nD) The thief was given a fair trial to him and sent to\nprison.\nE) Don't let yourself be laughed at.\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nGrammar and Structure Revision MCQ Test With Answers - Odd One Out\nExercise 4"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "d95e3da1-7789-440a-92bd-bc6c7fbfdb51",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "563_grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the odd one out.",
    "options": {
      "A": "\"I'd like to have a word with you.\" \"Yes, but what\ndo we have to talk about?\"",
      "B": "\"Did you have much trouble in getting a visa?\"\n\"Well, what do you think!\"",
      "C": "\"Do you think she'll succeed?\" \"I won't answer that\nquestion if you don't mind.\"",
      "D": "\"Who does want a sandwich\" \"I do.\"\nE) \"Who goes there?\" \"Prince Hamlet.\"\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nGrammar and Structure Revision MCQ Test With Answers - Odd One Out\nExercise 4"
    },
    "answer": "\"Who does want a sandwich\" \"I do.\"\nE) \"Who goes there?\" \"Prince Hamlet.\"\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/grammar-and-structure-revision-mcq-test-with-answers-odd-one-out-exercise-4/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nGrammar and Structure Revision MCQ Test With Answers - Odd One Out\nExercise 4"
  },
  {
    "id": "a8232b00-c555-4f80-ab17-3516abb65d9b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Gabriella has gone downtown ______ some supplies. 8. Look! That's ______ over there!",
    "options": {
      "A": "to get A) he",
      "B": "so to get B) my",
      "C": "for getting C) our",
      "D": "for to get D) him\nE) as to get E) I"
    },
    "answer": "to get A) he"
  },
  {
    "id": "5ac11a35-8bdc-44ce-88b7-671cc17a9864",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I'm sorry, but I don't really want to do it tonight. I 9. It was ______ that they were talking about, wasn't it?\n______ rather leave it till tomorrow.",
    "options": {
      "A": "not\nA) 'm",
      "B": "us\nB) had",
      "C": "they\nC) ' ve",
      "D": "who\nD) 'd\nE) we\nE) can"
    },
    "answer": "who\nD) 'd\nE) we\nE) can"
  },
  {
    "id": "c19d6f9e-8374-4909-8d90-6b21660c4910",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "It was him that went out just now, ______?\n3. There aren't very many people here, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "isn't it\nA) are they",
      "B": "wasn't it\nB) aren't they",
      "C": "isn't he\nC) are there",
      "D": "wasn't he\nD) isn't it\nE) it wasn't\nE) there are not"
    },
    "answer": "wasn't it\nB) aren't they"
  },
  {
    "id": "6f6c6cb6-ee3a-441c-8574-de1e6fa629e5",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The singing of the birds ______ me distant memories.\n4. Ali has a ______ vacation.",
    "options": {
      "A": "brings\nA) two-weeks",
      "B": "are bringing\nB) two week's",
      "C": "have brought\nC) two-weeks'",
      "D": "bring\nD) two week\nE) has been brought\nE) two-week"
    },
    "answer": "brings\nA) two-weeks"
  },
  {
    "id": "534cd0d7-dbfb-4869-97bc-cf80f1931a60",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "This is a song about a man who ______ by his wife and\n5. I ______ at seven o'clock, but ______ to be up by six. children.",
    "options": {
      "A": "get normally up / I sometimes have A) have been deserted",
      "B": "am normally getting up / I am having sometimes B) were deserted",
      "C": "normally get up / I am having sometimes C) has been deserting",
      "D": "get normally up / sometimes I have D) are deserted\nE) normally get up / sometimes I have E) has been deserted"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "27555a1b-1c17-43f9-b662-9deeeb8dd336",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I don't know how to play the guitar and ______. 13.We go to ______ school to study. We go to ______ work\nin order to earn a living. We go to ______ bed to rest",
    "options": {
      "A": "neither does my friend and sleep.",
      "B": "my friend doesn't neither\nA) -- / -- / --",
      "C": "neither my friend does\nB) -- / -- / the",
      "D": "either does my friend\nC) the / the / the\nE) my friend either doesn't\nD) the / --- / ---"
    },
    "answer": "neither does my friend and sleep."
  },
  {
    "id": "e622d095-2dc1-4a24-a1bc-51f365b68ac3",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______, all is not lost yet.\nE) --- / the / ---",
    "options": {
      "A": "In spite of the fact what the generals say 14.I'd rather have ______ of these two.",
      "B": "According to me\nA) the less expensive",
      "C": "Despite the fact what the generals say\nB) less expensive",
      "D": "Sometimes the time comes\nC) not so expensive\nE) According to the generals\nD) more expensive\nE) the least expensive\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nEnglish Grammar Level Test MCQ With Answers - Intermediate Part 3"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "f8ccfab8-021f-41aa-a2b4-f7fc0dd6056c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "615_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The price they charge for many types of colour TV 16.He ______ rather unwell for several days before he\nsets ______ finally dropping. died one night in his sleep.",
    "options": {
      "A": "more than A) had been feeling",
      "B": "are B) used to feel",
      "C": "is C) would have felt",
      "D": "were not D) should have felt\nE) begin E) will have been feeling\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-intermediate-part-3/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nEnglish Grammar Level Test MCQ With Answers - Intermediate Part 3"
    },
    "answer": "is C) would have felt"
  },
  {
    "id": "c8e1c505-9363-4ef3-af5b-3430c120e73a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Yes, I thought this morning I might need a new watch, 6. ______ AIDS threatens to spread further in the near\nbut they just changed the battery in my old watch future was discussed in a recent meeting.\nand it was working perfectly after all. So, I ______ a\nnew one.",
    "options": {
      "A": "The question of",
      "B": "As a matter of fact\nA) should not buy",
      "C": "Further proofs of\nB) had to buy",
      "D": "------------\nC) must have bought\nE) Whether or not\nD) needn't have bought"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "41af6593-5b34-4ea7-a34a-5eedaf9cf837",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "You ______ another job pretty soon. I have a feeling\nE) didn't need to buy\nthat you're going to get fired before long.\n2.\nIt is Meltem's birthday party... Nil, a close friend, asks",
    "options": {
      "A": "would rather start looking for\nher:",
      "B": "had better to start looking for",
      "C": "would start looking for",
      "D": "'d better to start to look for\nNİL: How come Aysel isn't here? Didn't you send her\nan invitation? E) 'd better start looking for"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "588caae9-6d87-4d6a-9e7a-d775004f41ba",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______, he went to collect his payment.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Having finished his work successfully\nMELTEM: I ______ send her one, but I think it ______ in\nthe mail.",
      "B": "Although he had completed his work successfully",
      "C": "In view of the work was completed with success",
      "D": "Despite the fact that the work was successfully\nA) would / was lost completed\nB) should / got lost E) Despite he didn't finish the job\nC) could / may get lost 9. It seems to me that they never gave a thought to\nD) did / must have got lost probable future problems when the plans ______ five\nyears ago.\nE) might / must be lost"
    },
    "answer": "Having finished his work successfully\nMELTEM: I ______ send her one, but I think it ______ in\nthe mail."
  },
  {
    "id": "4c1f556f-1bca-43e4-87fa-77b1bdc57c09",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I understand you did send him an e-mail message,",
    "options": {
      "A": "they laid down\nbut somehow it got lost on the way and he didn't turn",
      "B": "were not laid down\nup for the interview. I think you ______ him instead.",
      "C": "to be laid down\nA) ought to have phoned",
      "D": "had been laid down\nB) should phone E) were being laid down\nC) couldn't have phoned 10.Haven't you heard the news? Some of the astronauts,\nD) had not phoned ______ objected to the new regulations, have asked to\nbe dropped from the Apollo program.\nE) must have phoned"
    },
    "answer": "they laid down\nbut somehow it got lost on the way and he didn't turn"
  },
  {
    "id": "d36d0f9b-9ce8-46b5-a2e4-e4f670f51ffd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Have you heard the news, Abdullah? The man ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "when they\nrefused your proposal last year has been arrested.",
      "B": "that",
      "C": "whom\nA) while he",
      "D": "whose wives\nB) whom\nE) who has repeatedly\nC) when he\nD) whose daughter 11.On top of the hill ______.\nE) who have\nA) an Ottoman citadel stood enormous"
    },
    "answer": "whose wives\nB) whom\nE) who has repeatedly\nC) when he\nD) whose daughter 11.On top of the hill ______.\nE) who have\nA) an Ottoman citadel stood enormous"
  },
  {
    "id": "6fb65747-3584-4147-b024-5891765ae600",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "You don't believe every citizen is born free and equal\nB) an enormous Ottoman citadel stood\nand shares the same inherent human dignity, ______?\nC) stood an enormous Ottoman citadel",
    "options": {
      "A": "aren't they D) the enormous Ottoman citadel stood",
      "B": "does he or she E) the Ottoman citadel enormous stood",
      "C": "don't they",
      "D": "doesn't he or she\nE) do you\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nEnglish Grammar Level Test MCQ With Answers - Advanced Part 4"
    },
    "answer": null
  },
  {
    "id": "75783b7a-cbb6-4d68-b95c-b2eca1be4de7",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "He dyed his hair and wore dark glasses ______ people 18.They were wondering what ______.\nwouldn't recognize him.",
    "options": {
      "A": "was it that the man wanted to have\nA) if only",
      "B": "did the man want to say\nB) so that",
      "C": "was it wanted by the man\nC) never again",
      "D": "it was that the man wanted to have\nD) never again\nE) was it that the man said\nE) in order to"
    },
    "answer": "did the man want to say\nB) so that"
  },
  {
    "id": "3cdc4673-63f4-40a8-b27e-b128424af710",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the correct question form:\n13.______ rich people are, they always seem anxious to\nmake ______ more money.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Who waited for you?",
      "B": "Who waited for you?\nA) No matter how / still",
      "C": "Who for you waited?\nB) Some / any",
      "D": "You waited for who?\nC) So / much\nE) For who you waited?\nD) Whatever / some"
    },
    "answer": "Who waited for you?"
  },
  {
    "id": "789cfbd7-3bdc-45d0-a2e3-633389d09251",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Oh, I am really sorry. I wish I ______ that vase.\nE) The / never\n14.I'm surprised to hear that you've seen him here in",
    "options": {
      "A": "had never attempted to lift\nIzmir because he is supposed ______ abroad for some",
      "B": "can pay for\ntime now.",
      "C": "would buy\nA) to be",
      "D": "won't have needed\nB) to have been E) wouldn't have broken\nC) being 21.Oh, how I wish I ______ there with you last night!\nD) having been\nA) were\nE) to being\nB) was"
    },
    "answer": "had never attempted to lift\nIzmir because he is supposed ______ abroad for some"
  },
  {
    "id": "3739805e-9d71-4429-a895-d19623938c19",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I remember ______ to a big mosque in Istanbul as a\nsmall child. C) had been\nD) am",
    "options": {
      "A": "their taking E) have been",
      "B": "to take them\n22.They had the poor man ______ the toilets twice a day.",
      "C": "being taken",
      "D": "to have taken them A) cleaned\nE) to be taken B) to clean"
    },
    "answer": "being taken"
  },
  {
    "id": "0dfb83f1-50cf-4121-969e-5c325cdece86",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The doctor recommended that I ______ more careful C) cleans\nwith my diet. D) should clean\nE) clean",
    "options": {
      "A": "be\n23.O.K., boys. It's high time we all ______ home now.",
      "B": "will be",
      "C": "am A) have gone",
      "D": "was B) go\nE) were C) will go"
    },
    "answer": "be\n23.O.K., boys. It's high time we all ______ home now."
  },
  {
    "id": "6a94d286-a6d5-4a84-8035-0a4992e2c065",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Never before in my life ______ before a cruel tyrant! D) had gone\nE) went",
    "options": {
      "A": "have I had to bow\n24.Not only ______ our display windows, but they also",
      "B": "I had bowed\nchoose the different kinds of materials to be used in",
      "C": "I should have bowed the background.",
      "D": "I needn't have bowed\nA) design professional interior decorators do\nE) I must have bowed\nB) professional interior decorators do design\nC) do professional interior decorators design\nD) do design professional interior decorators\nE) design do professional interior decorators\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nEnglish Grammar Level Test MCQ With Answers - Advanced Part 4"
    },
    "answer": "have I had to bow\n24.Not only ______ our display windows, but they also"
  },
  {
    "id": "86b9c01b-411f-4ee1-bdab-6acb177706ce",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "616_english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Choose the correct sentence:",
    "options": {
      "A": "Is huge thing man-made that?",
      "B": "Is that huge thing man-made?",
      "C": "Is that huge man-made thing?",
      "D": "Is that thing man-made huge?\nE) Is that thing huge man-made?\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/english-grammar-level-test-mcq-with-answers-advanced-part-4/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nEnglish Grammar Level Test MCQ With Answers - Advanced Part 4"
    },
    "answer": "Is that huge thing man-made?"
  },
  {
    "id": "07d1330c-7109-43e7-95bd-b2a48f89fff9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Are there any volunteers? ______ who’s tall will do. 9. I often like to spend time ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "One A) myself",
      "B": "Anything B) by myself",
      "C": "Something C) on myself",
      "D": "Anyone D) on me own"
    },
    "answer": "Anyone D) on me own"
  },
  {
    "id": "3261aba2-f2bb-497c-bc96-c3304e8e7d22",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ you say, I won’t believe you. 10.– Do you need help? – No, thanks. I can do it ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Whoever A) on myself",
      "B": "Whichever B) on my own",
      "C": "Whatever C) by my own",
      "D": "No matter D) with yours"
    },
    "answer": "Whatever C) by my own"
  },
  {
    "id": "3645fde7-56bf-4cc0-8f43-46b2636225b4",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Did you enjoy ______ at the beach, Joy? 11.I hate that smelly dog of ______. Take it away at once!",
    "options": {
      "A": "you\nA) your",
      "B": "yourself\nB) yours",
      "C": "your self\nC) you",
      "D": "yours\nD) there’s"
    },
    "answer": "yourself\nB) yours"
  },
  {
    "id": "08ca1cc1-23f8-405e-b13f-5040976d11d0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "One prefers to shop at Harrods, ______?\n12.Who are ______ people over there?",
    "options": {
      "A": "doesn’t one\nA) that",
      "B": "doesn’t it\nB) these",
      "C": "don’t you\nC) those",
      "D": "does one\nD) —"
    },
    "answer": "doesn’t one\nA) that"
  },
  {
    "id": "d4c9b6e3-7a82-4396-bd8a-12039e62c2aa",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I like this painting but I don’t think much of those\n______. 13.We’ve hardly got ______ cat food left.",
    "options": {
      "A": "rest A) no",
      "B": "other B) some",
      "C": "ones C) any",
      "D": "besides D) a"
    },
    "answer": "ones C) any"
  },
  {
    "id": "a810c517-b886-476c-9f15-abb6dc2274ae",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ believes in ghosts is a bit crazy! 14.– Do you want me to give you a helping hand?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Whatever – Thank you! I can do it ______.",
      "B": "Everybody\nA) on myself",
      "C": "Everyone\nB) by myself",
      "D": "Anyone who\nC) with myself"
    },
    "answer": "Anyone who\nC) with myself"
  },
  {
    "id": "dbefbf19-7d83-4c81-947f-ca5c663682de",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "It’s not pleasant to hear oneself described by ______\nD) without your hand\nemployees.\n15.Could I have ______ drink?",
    "options": {
      "A": "his\nA) other",
      "B": "their’s\nB) an other",
      "C": "your\nC) the another",
      "D": "one’s\nD) another"
    },
    "answer": "one’s\nD) another"
  },
  {
    "id": "add102bd-3d76-4dbb-a765-ab90db01f6aa",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Please invite ______ you like to the reception.\n16.– Will you lend me some money?",
    "options": {
      "A": "these\n– No, I can’t. I don’t have ______.",
      "B": "anyone",
      "C": "ones\nA) some",
      "D": "all\nB) any\nC) none\nD) One\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 02"
    },
    "answer": "anyone"
  },
  {
    "id": "0ee0ed6e-d890-4958-bdeb-ca2b311d7f9d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Take your feet off the table ______ legs aren’t very 21.A dog’s intelligence is much greater than ______ of a\nstrong. cat.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Your A) that",
      "B": "His B) its",
      "C": "It’s C) it",
      "D": "Its D) what"
    },
    "answer": "Its D) what"
  },
  {
    "id": "181b2d31-cbe9-4886-a5b6-f9471ce6d98d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Paranoids talk to ______ a lot. Talking to oneself is the 22.The manageress spoke to me ______.\nfirst sign of madness.",
    "options": {
      "A": "by herself\nA) each other",
      "B": "oneself\nB) one another",
      "C": "on her own\nC) themselves",
      "D": "herself\nD) himself"
    },
    "answer": "on her own\nC) themselves"
  },
  {
    "id": "49f96ea3-e7f1-4287-b97a-071b6c6bffac",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Rachel has hardly ______ sympathy for her brother’s\n19.I don’t want to go ______ too expensive. drinking problem.",
    "options": {
      "A": "nowhere A) some",
      "B": "somewhere B) any",
      "C": "no way C) no",
      "D": "anywhere D) many"
    },
    "answer": "somewhere B) any"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d976c33-e95f-4139-891a-f992d8f42931",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I’ll go and see the President ______ if I have to. 24.We never touched ______ of the money.",
    "options": {
      "A": "on myself A) no",
      "B": "oneself B) none",
      "C": "himself C) any",
      "D": "by himself D) some"
    },
    "answer": "himself C) any"
  },
  {
    "id": "76139576-7b77-454e-98ff-a28d4993fcf2",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "702_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Let’s go ______ nice for a drink.",
    "options": {
      "A": "anywhere",
      "B": "where",
      "C": "there",
      "D": "somewhere\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 02"
    },
    "answer": "somewhere\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-02/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 02"
  },
  {
    "id": "d21195fe-f439-40c9-9dc5-990a9f9d316d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I really think that apologising is ______ you can do. 8. He’s a far ______ intelligent person than my brother.",
    "options": {
      "A": "not as enough as A) lesser",
      "B": "a little B) more",
      "C": "the least C) fewer",
      "D": "as far as D) much"
    },
    "answer": "the least C) fewer"
  },
  {
    "id": "09ceeebf-6a8f-4ee1-9c7d-c24b0fc03738",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "– How do you like your coffee? 9. You are working too slowly. You’d better work ______!\n– ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "a bit faster",
      "B": "a piece faster\nA) More stronger the better",
      "C": "a bit more fast\nB) The strong the good",
      "D": "an item more fast\nC) More strong more good"
    },
    "answer": "an item more fast\nC) More strong more good"
  },
  {
    "id": "c6667877-6a8c-4e5f-be0c-a8fe2dac36f4",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "“Oh, I beg your pardon!” cried Alice ______ than it was\nD) The stronger the better\nnecessary.\n3. I’ve never owned ______ independent cat like this\none!",
    "options": {
      "A": "hasty",
      "B": "hastilier\nA) a more than",
      "C": "most hastily\nB) such an",
      "D": "more hastily\nC) a so"
    },
    "answer": "more hastily\nC) a so"
  },
  {
    "id": "083d37b8-5d57-462b-9507-44ff1ed1580f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Because of the excellent faculty, King High students\nD) as much an\ngo far, ______ than students in other high schools.\n4. I can’t stand this weather. It’s getting ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "much far\nA) more and more",
      "B": "more far\nB) worse and worse",
      "C": "less further\nC) coldest and coldest",
      "D": "much further\nD) further and further"
    },
    "answer": "much further\nD) further and further"
  },
  {
    "id": "00799ff4-d4fe-4a35-8428-d563e6a8d6af",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Alice wasn’t ______ of the Liddle girls. There were\n5. Paula has been working ______ than before. Her speed three of them if I’m not mistaken.\nis amazing!",
    "options": {
      "A": "youngest\nA) quicklier",
      "B": "younger\nB) slowlier",
      "C": "the eldest\nC) more slowly",
      "D": "the elder\nD) more quickly"
    },
    "answer": "the eldest\nC) more slowly"
  },
  {
    "id": "860f4807-eca7-4e65-93b6-00cb271fb821",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Andy’s the cleverest of them all, but Sue is ______.\n6. Brian has been working ______ since he was\npromoted.",
    "options": {
      "A": "less lazy",
      "B": "more lazy\nA) much harder",
      "C": "laziest\nB) as harder",
      "D": "most hardworking\nC) just as hardly"
    },
    "answer": "less lazy"
  },
  {
    "id": "37f417da-6aa8-46fc-9937-164b40c6440c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "German is ______ than English.\nD) more hardly\n7. In some ways, walking is ______ than travelling by bus",
    "options": {
      "A": "not as difficult\nor car.",
      "B": "not as easy",
      "C": "more easier\nA) more less harmful",
      "D": "more difficult\nB) much more healthier\nC) less harmfully 15.She’s much taller ______ me.\nD) much healthier\nA) than\nB) as\nC) then\nD) That\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 03"
    },
    "answer": "more difficult\nB) much more healthier\nC) less harmfully 15.She’s much taller ______ me.\nD) much healthier\nA) than\nB) as\nC) then\nD) That\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 03"
  },
  {
    "id": "f4247067-3b0b-4f28-bf90-8484d919d6ae",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "A Ford is ______ than a Volvo. 21.You look ______ than usual.",
    "options": {
      "A": "much expensive A) even more beautiful",
      "B": "too much expensive B) twice as beautiful",
      "C": "much more expensive C) not as beautiful",
      "D": "not so expensive D) not so beautiful"
    },
    "answer": "much more expensive C) not as beautiful"
  },
  {
    "id": "dcdc37b3-e6e6-4bb1-9b9a-1ce74d35fa04",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Living in the country is not ______ as living in the city. 22.I have only a few debts, but my sister has even ______\ndebts than I do.",
    "options": {
      "A": "more expensive\nA) lesser",
      "B": "so expensive\nB) less",
      "C": "less expensive\nC) more",
      "D": "such expensive\nD) fewer"
    },
    "answer": "so expensive\nB) less"
  },
  {
    "id": "8dfce152-0d68-4d73-a44a-36ad87293bf9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I would sleep ______ if I weren’t worried about Tom.\n23.She’s twice as ______ as her sister",
    "options": {
      "A": "peaceful\nA) livelier",
      "B": "more peaceful\nB) lively",
      "C": "more peacefully\nC) liveliest",
      "D": "less peacefully\nD) more lively"
    },
    "answer": "more peacefully\nC) liveliest"
  },
  {
    "id": "781364b8-58c8-4a82-b9df-0945c509416a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Can you eat a bit faster ______ that?\n24.Nurses handle babies gently, but new mothers",
    "options": {
      "A": "then handle them the ______ of all.",
      "B": "as\nA) gentliest",
      "C": "so\nB) gentlier",
      "D": "than\nC) most gently"
    },
    "answer": "than\nC) most gently"
  },
  {
    "id": "859974ff-5263-47e5-a151-4036997c6ca3",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "703_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The train isn’t ______ than the bus.\nD) more gently",
    "options": {
      "A": "no quick 25.We’ve all got terrible voices, but I sing ______ of all.",
      "B": "no quicker\nA) worse",
      "C": "twice as quick\nB) bad",
      "D": "any quicker\nC) worst\nD) more bad\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 03"
    },
    "answer": "any quicker\nC) worst\nD) more bad\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-03/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 03"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0793bce-9194-443e-88c0-f58459cfc601",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "How much money ______ him this time? 9. Say it again, I ______ you.",
    "options": {
      "A": "are you owing A) don’t listen to",
      "B": "are you owning B) am not listening",
      "C": "do you own C) am not hearing",
      "D": "do you owe D) don’t hear"
    },
    "answer": "do you owe D) don’t hear"
  },
  {
    "id": "4412703e-e459-4921-8d86-bc96c68c236a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Look at her! She ______ the soup to see if it needs 10.– Would you like a cup of coffee, Dr Ho?\nmore salt.\n– Oh no, thanks. It ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "tastes\nA) is smelling delicious, but I am not drinking coffee.",
      "B": "taste\nB) smells delicious, but I don’t drink coffee.",
      "C": "has now been tasting\nC) is smelling delicious, but I don’t drink coffee.",
      "D": "is tasting\nD) smells delicious, but I am not drinking coffee at"
    },
    "answer": "is tasting\nD) smells delicious, but I am not drinking coffee at"
  },
  {
    "id": "62a22ab9-a8ed-481e-a496-87913a638315",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The milk ______ sour. Have you been keeping it for a\nlong time? all.\n11.This estate has no permanent owner! Who ______ this",
    "options": {
      "A": "is smelling time?",
      "B": "isn’t smelling\nA) belonged it",
      "C": "smells\nB) belongs it",
      "D": "is being smelt\nC) does it belong to"
    },
    "answer": "smells\nB) belongs it"
  },
  {
    "id": "fc7a5a51-f015-46c5-ab78-a248376a7cd4",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I tried a bit of the cake to see how it ______.\nD) is belonging it to",
    "options": {
      "A": "tasted 12.Come and sit by Leo and me. We ______ a boring",
      "B": "tastes gossip all about Clinton’s affair. Join us if you are\ninterested.",
      "C": "was tasting",
      "D": "is tasting\nA) have been having"
    },
    "answer": "tasted 12.Come and sit by Leo and me. We ______ a boring"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9b9c2d2-ac0c-405f-9c01-e7b298bbf9e2",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "This soup ______ of disinfectant. B) have had\nC) have",
    "options": {
      "A": "taste\nD) are having",
      "B": "tastes\n13.I think it is a pity you don’t take more exercise. You",
      "C": "is tasting\n______ fat.",
      "D": "have got a taste"
    },
    "answer": "tastes\n13.I think it is a pity you don’t take more exercise. You"
  },
  {
    "id": "b251003e-e537-4f9b-bb5c-d8c7ab5ffa5b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "That bottle ______ petrol and we used it as an",
    "options": {
      "A": "are getting\nexplosive.",
      "B": "have to get",
      "C": "get\nA) contains",
      "D": "had got\nB) is containing"
    },
    "answer": "get\nA) contains"
  },
  {
    "id": "6862841b-3344-439f-9359-65576435ab26",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Look at this sign. It ______ here ‘Leave your car here.’\nC) contained\nWhy not park our car here?\nD) was containing\n7. – What are you doing?",
    "options": {
      "A": "reads",
      "B": "is reading\n– I ______ to get this car started.",
      "C": "is writing",
      "D": "is advising\nA) am wanting\nB) will want 15.Tom and Mr. Pitt ______ a stormy conversation. I\nwonder what they are talking about.\nC) will be wanting\nD) want\nA) has been having"
    },
    "answer": "reads"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca8fd74d-83fd-4ac5-91fc-a8cf30dea883",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "‘I love this hair-do – my hair ______ so modern now.’ B) have had\nC) are having",
    "options": {
      "A": "looks\nD) have",
      "B": "are looking",
      "C": "are being looked",
      "D": "look\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 04"
    },
    "answer": "looks\nD) have"
  },
  {
    "id": "86709689-ce5b-48f2-a7f8-4c737bbd887e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "– Who ______ champagne? – Me, when I can afford it. 21.You know the current situation: cinema audiences\n______ in the United States now.",
    "options": {
      "A": "has drunk\nA) decline",
      "B": "drank\nB) are declining",
      "C": "drinks\nC) decrease",
      "D": "is drinking\nD) is decreasing"
    },
    "answer": "drinks\nC) decrease"
  },
  {
    "id": "8b98a5ad-cf85-4ffb-a107-24b59da39da8",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "– What ______ at?\n22.I can’t interrupt him just now. He ____ a phone call to\n– A strange bird is flying over there. Australia at the moment.",
    "options": {
      "A": "do you look A) is being made",
      "B": "did you look B) makes",
      "C": "are you looking C) is making",
      "D": "were you looking D) has made"
    },
    "answer": "are you looking C) is making"
  },
  {
    "id": "e9b66177-e4ab-4d50-b768-d6d19ebdb0c6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Hi, Mike. I’m in France now. Can you imagine what a 23.– The telephone is ringing, Ann. Can you get it?\ngreat time I ______?\n– No, I ______ dinner. Maybe a little bit later.",
    "options": {
      "A": "have\nA) have",
      "B": "enjoy\nB) am having",
      "C": "am having\nC) am being had",
      "D": "have had\nD) I had"
    },
    "answer": "am having\nC) am being had"
  },
  {
    "id": "5dab830c-7851-449c-a1e8-287d6e50dfd1",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "– the violin now? – Actually, that’s the radio you hear\nnow. 24.Paris is wonderful! I like the food here, and so I ______\nlike mad.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Does your son play\nA) am eating",
      "B": "Who plays\nB) have eaten",
      "C": "How long has your son been playing\nC) had eaten",
      "D": "Is your son playing\nD) am not eating"
    },
    "answer": "Is your son playing\nD) am not eating"
  },
  {
    "id": "27ef4111-1041-4c97-adae-3c3866b49bec",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "704_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Scientists believe the weather ______ now.\n25.Whitman is a historian. He ____ on a history of cross-",
    "options": {
      "A": "is changing cultural dating customs.",
      "B": "changes\nA) currently works",
      "C": "was changed\nB) works now",
      "D": "changed\nC) is currently working\nD) currently write\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-04/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 04"
    },
    "answer": "is changing cultural dating customs."
  },
  {
    "id": "9ebd6cdd-13e0-4919-a5da-15527d274685",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "One manufacturer, Smart Transport, Inc., ______ a 8. Next year the taxpayers ______ over twenty-two\npress conference every other month. million dollars for a transportation system that is\nalready out-of-date.",
    "options": {
      "A": "holds\nA) will spend",
      "B": "had held\nB) will be spending",
      "C": "shall hold\nC) will have spent",
      "D": "is holding\nD) will have been spending"
    },
    "answer": "holds\nA) will spend"
  },
  {
    "id": "f9d31b5b-9545-473d-a18c-f2bcd338f7c0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Lucy ______ for a drink this evening. I invited her\nyesterday. 9. She’ll pay us back when she ______ a job.",
    "options": {
      "A": "comes A) gets",
      "B": "is coming B) have",
      "C": "will come C) will get",
      "D": "shall come D) shall get"
    },
    "answer": "is coming B) have"
  },
  {
    "id": "e6fd2f93-e933-46b0-bdaf-ff1fe625299b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "By early in the 21st century, one in four Japanese 10.Don’t sweep the floor, before your parents ______.\npeople _____ over sixty-five.",
    "options": {
      "A": "arrived\nA) will be",
      "B": "arrives\nB) shall be",
      "C": "will arrive\nC) is",
      "D": "arrive\nD) is required to be"
    },
    "answer": "arrived\nA) will be"
  },
  {
    "id": "66db3f98-eb5c-4476-8855-56ffeee97a1e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Will you stay here until ______ off?\n4. I’ll think of you when ______ on the beach next week.",
    "options": {
      "A": "the plane will take\nA) I’m being laid",
      "B": "shall the plane take\nB) I’m going to lie",
      "C": "the plane takes\nC) I’ll be lying",
      "D": "the plane have taken\nD) I’m lying"
    },
    "answer": "the plane takes\nC) I’ll be lying"
  },
  {
    "id": "7ce316f1-8cc7-4b7d-b0cd-2d9ad6c9fef4",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I won’t tell you my secret unless you ______ not to tell\n5. The builders say they ______ the roof by Tuesday. anyone.",
    "options": {
      "A": "will finish A) will promise",
      "B": "are finishing B) don’t promise",
      "C": "will have finished C) promise",
      "D": "will be finishing D) won’t promise"
    },
    "answer": "will have finished C) promise"
  },
  {
    "id": "98455052-0ed6-409e-b4e9-5a44bcbeef7c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "He promised that he ______ call my mother to wish 13.Whenever ______ a thunder-storm, the cat hides\nher a happy birthday. under the bed.",
    "options": {
      "A": "will A) there’ll be",
      "B": "would B) there’s",
      "C": "used to C) there was",
      "D": "would get used to D) there will be"
    },
    "answer": "would B) there’s"
  },
  {
    "id": "492ce50b-8a29-4531-a81a-2793be2bb805",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Before the construction of the English Channel, which 14.Your little robot dog will wag his tail if you ______ him\nconnects France and England, most people didn’t on the floor.\nbelieve that travel by land between the two countries\n______ possible in the twentieth century.",
    "options": {
      "A": "place",
      "B": "will place\nA) will be",
      "C": "had placed\nB) would be",
      "D": "are placing\nC) used to be\nD) is going to be\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 07"
    },
    "answer": "will place\nA) will be"
  },
  {
    "id": "800b9edc-ecab-45e2-aa3c-1fded08d396d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Your little robot dog will even bark if you ______ sound 20.He took me for his housemaid. How surprised he’ll be\nfiles info his body. when he ______ out who I am!",
    "options": {
      "A": "put A) found",
      "B": "had put B) will find",
      "C": "will put C) shall find",
      "D": "are put D) finds"
    },
    "answer": "put A) found"
  },
  {
    "id": "4e1dc4b3-95dd-45e8-81db-17b484bb93e9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Unless they ______ ticket prices, I’m not going to fly 21.I’ll be surprised if he ______ an accident soon. He\nanymore. I’m not that rich. drives like crazy.",
    "options": {
      "A": "don’t lower A) won’t have",
      "B": "will not lowered B) doesn’t have",
      "C": "will lower C) will have",
      "D": "lower D) has"
    },
    "answer": "lower D) has"
  },
  {
    "id": "3e4be05c-54e3-4588-b03a-a8d270ccc8c5",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "If I was free for six months, I ______ around the world. 22.If he ______ for you, he’ll be very angry.",
    "options": {
      "A": "travelled A) still waits",
      "B": "would travel B) will still wait",
      "C": "travel C) will still be waiting",
      "D": "will travel D) is still waiting"
    },
    "answer": "would travel B) will still wait"
  },
  {
    "id": "f7c74e37-3cd7-4338-95d3-256628f43513",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Your roommate is really noisy. If I ______ with him, I’d 23.If ______ you what you’re doing say you’re with me.\ntalk to him about the problem.",
    "options": {
      "A": "nobody’ll ask\nA) lived",
      "B": "anybody asks\nB) will live",
      "C": "nobody asks\nC) live",
      "D": "anybody will ask\nD) would live"
    },
    "answer": "nobody’ll ask\nA) lived"
  },
  {
    "id": "63e09477-ce1d-4997-8fbf-429d69bd4765",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ him I’m ashamed.\n19.If I didn’t like flying that much, I ______ a pilot.",
    "options": {
      "A": "If I saw\nA) would",
      "B": "Whenever I see\nB) became",
      "C": "If I’ll see\nC) won’t be",
      "D": "Whenever I’ll meet\nD) wouldn’t be"
    },
    "answer": "Whenever I see\nB) became"
  },
  {
    "id": "b261190c-d2da-4239-89d2-46dd66b8091a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "707_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "If Bob ______ your letter, I’m sure he’ll phone you\ntoday.",
    "options": {
      "A": "will receive",
      "B": "will have received",
      "C": "has received",
      "D": "receive\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-07/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 07"
    },
    "answer": "has received"
  },
  {
    "id": "b223dd51-62fc-4ebd-bbdd-a4fccc63b1c2",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Our first Spanish and Japanese editions of Modern 8. The traffic is so heavy nowadays that people ______\nReader ______ this year, and they have already found on the roads daily.\na large audience.",
    "options": {
      "A": "are killed\nA) published",
      "B": "kill\nB) were published",
      "C": "killing\nC) were publishing",
      "D": "killed\nD) publish"
    },
    "answer": "kill\nB) were published"
  },
  {
    "id": "21434df1-45c4-4611-8c69-bc4074dd7d04",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Tickets ______ from any travel agent or directly from\n2. Until after World War II, almost all the automobiles the airline.\ndriven in the US ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "may be purchased\nA) made in Detroit by automobile workers",
      "B": "may purchase\nB) have been made in Detroit",
      "C": "purchase\nC) were made in Detroit by automobile workers",
      "D": "purchased\nD) made in Detroit"
    },
    "answer": "may be purchased\nA) made in Detroit by automobile workers"
  },
  {
    "id": "dec4bc20-2c3c-4f5b-abf4-dfb3f50a96cf",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "This method of decorating metal ______ invented in\n3. The driver of the car ______ in the accident. the Middle East and perfected by the Chinese,\nJapanese, and French.",
    "options": {
      "A": "hurt seriously\nA) probably",
      "B": "seriously hurt\nB) was probably",
      "C": "was seriously hurt\nC) had probably",
      "D": "seriously hurts\nD) –"
    },
    "answer": "seriously hurt\nB) was probably"
  },
  {
    "id": "0dc84632-f680-4d42-9eef-f48ee27d7bbe",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The vegetables ______ up, what shall we do now?\n11.The Great Wall of China was the only man-made",
    "options": {
      "A": "cutted structure on earth which ______ when they were\ncircling the dirt.",
      "B": "have cut",
      "C": "are all cut\nA) could see by the astronauts",
      "D": "are cutted\nB) could be seen by the astronauts"
    },
    "answer": "are all cut\nA) could see by the astronauts"
  },
  {
    "id": "ebbd958b-2b54-4b46-8bdb-17c00519034a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The furniture ______ for firewood. C) the astronauts could be seen\nD) could see the astronauts",
    "options": {
      "A": "was broke\n12.The Battle of Hastings ______ in 1066.",
      "B": "was broken up",
      "C": "break up\nA) fought",
      "D": "broke up\nB) was fought"
    },
    "answer": "was broken up"
  },
  {
    "id": "1c7c6999-ab7d-437f-a55a-22bdc292e066",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I ______ by Mary’s wanting to tell everybody what to C) was fighted\ndo.\nD) being fought",
    "options": {
      "A": "annoyed 13.My computer ______ viruses every six months.",
      "B": "was annoyed\nA) is being checked for",
      "C": "annoy\nB) checks with",
      "D": "had annoyed\nC) is checked by"
    },
    "answer": "was annoyed\nA) is being checked for"
  },
  {
    "id": "b24972eb-ab08-4b97-84d2-d22080b72c90",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The positive hydrogen atoms ______ to the negative\nD) is checked for\noxygen atoms.\n14.Blair is not in his room, and his bed ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "attract\nA) doesn’t sleep in",
      "B": "are being attracted\nB) doesn’t touched",
      "C": "are attracted\nC) hasn’t been slept in",
      "D": "will never be attracted\nD) hasn’t been slept\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 09"
    },
    "answer": "are attracted\nC) hasn’t been slept in"
  },
  {
    "id": "9c92f610-1c8e-4078-ac95-b4d57e5e4b9b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Channels ______ by using the remote control. 20.When my mother phoned her Liz ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "can change A) interviewed",
      "B": "can switch (on, off) B) was being interviewed",
      "C": "can be switching (on, off) C) is interviewing",
      "D": "can be changed D) is being interviewed"
    },
    "answer": "can be changed D) is being interviewed"
  },
  {
    "id": "8c342344-6582-4135-b485-9211fe42d237",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The cable TV ______ my personal computer. 21.Excuse the mess; the house ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "connects A) is being painted",
      "B": "is connected B) paints",
      "C": "is connected to C) is painting",
      "D": "keeps in touch with D) is painted"
    },
    "answer": "is connected to C) is painting"
  },
  {
    "id": "6b56e149-eccd-4c75-9b45-a5633961c1c9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "CD-ROMS are much better than books because much 22.What a pity! All the washing machines ______ now.\ninformation can ______ on them.",
    "options": {
      "A": "are used\nA) store",
      "B": "are been used\nB) storage",
      "C": "are being used\nC) be stored",
      "D": "are using\nD) be storing"
    },
    "answer": "are being used\nC) be stored"
  },
  {
    "id": "29280f39-60c1-44e3-a4a1-4ccccfacd8d8",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "He ______ stealing the money by our sales manager.\n18.The Internet should ______ the government.",
    "options": {
      "A": "was\nA) control",
      "B": "is\nB) be controlled by",
      "C": "caught\nC) be controlled with",
      "D": "was caught\nD) be under the control by"
    },
    "answer": "was caught\nD) be under the control by"
  },
  {
    "id": "8887886b-e306-4a71-8a5f-9857a412eb61",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "My resume ______ to the statement of purpose.\n19.I felt as if ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "includes\nA) I watch",
      "B": "attach\nB) I am being watched",
      "C": "is attached\nC) I was being watched",
      "D": "attaches\nD) I have watched"
    },
    "answer": "is attached\nC) I was being watched"
  },
  {
    "id": "f9fd51ea-454e-4e64-a381-67ebc05e11f7",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "709_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "A disqualified driver has ______ to prison.",
    "options": {
      "A": "sent",
      "B": "to send",
      "C": "to be",
      "D": "to be sent\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 09"
    },
    "answer": "to be sent\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-09/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 09"
  },
  {
    "id": "aecd4f56-0ea2-4750-9a31-4d32297700df",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Because of an extremely high accident rate, 9. There is a lot of work ______ here.\nrestrictions on the teenagers' ______ will be discussed\nat the next City Council meeting.",
    "options": {
      "A": "doing",
      "B": "to do\nA) drive",
      "C": "do\nB) having driving",
      "D": "to not do\nC) driving"
    },
    "answer": "do\nB) having driving"
  },
  {
    "id": "6c75c30d-66b2-48e2-a551-daf9357ca837",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "She has a terrible fear of ______ alone.\nD) to drive\n2. You were a fool ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "be",
      "B": "to be\nA) to agreeing",
      "C": "being\nB) agreeing",
      "D": "to being\nC) agree"
    },
    "answer": "being\nB) agreeing"
  },
  {
    "id": "7d32117a-7120-43cc-bd2f-05508983d2ee",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The Japanese art of origami is created by ______\nD) to agree\npaper into various forms.\n3. I hope to have a chance of ______ you again.",
    "options": {
      "A": "fold\nA) to see",
      "B": "to fold\nB) seeing",
      "C": "to have folded\nC) having seen",
      "D": "folding\nD) being seen"
    },
    "answer": "folding\nD) being seen"
  },
  {
    "id": "14e25ec9-01b1-4461-b275-421f57d4936f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Let’s just keep on ______.\n4. I’m sorry to ______ you.",
    "options": {
      "A": "dance\nA) disturbing",
      "B": "to dance\nB) the disturbing",
      "C": "dancing\nC) disturb",
      "D": "to dancing\nD) disturbed"
    },
    "answer": "dancing\nC) disturb"
  },
  {
    "id": "b5d752ef-1fd0-4320-9e2b-0e90cff40544",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "– What do you want to do tonight?\n5. They were quite content with ______ where they were.\n– I feel like ______ to a movie.",
    "options": {
      "A": "stay A) to go",
      "B": "to stay B) to going",
      "C": "be staying C) going",
      "D": "staying D) go"
    },
    "answer": "be staying C) going"
  },
  {
    "id": "03e4799f-ff35-4326-94bd-48bc61749414",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "They agreed on ______ the profits equally. 14.I am not good ______ letters.",
    "options": {
      "A": "to share A) to write",
      "B": "share B) to writing",
      "C": "sharing C) at writing",
      "D": "to sharing D) to be writing"
    },
    "answer": "sharing C) at writing"
  },
  {
    "id": "dce756f1-7ac6-41dd-b7d2-8c066079fcb6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "We are in favour of ______ the bridge. 15.Do you often go ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "build A) to fish",
      "B": "building B) to fishing",
      "C": "to build C) fishing",
      "D": "having been built D) fish"
    },
    "answer": "building B) to fishing"
  },
  {
    "id": "9b4a57a8-1f44-4a9e-b9fc-22bf6c1696cb",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I hate the idea of ______ old.",
    "options": {
      "A": "to get",
      "B": "get",
      "C": "to become",
      "D": "getting\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 11"
    },
    "answer": "getting\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 11"
  },
  {
    "id": "9d532c08-34cc-4a67-a72a-8710d3078b6a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "At the moment that the plane touched down safely, 21.I look forward ______ from you.\nthe passengers expressed their gratitude for having\nsurvived the terrifying flight by ______ the pilot and",
    "options": {
      "A": "to hear\nthe crew.",
      "B": "hear",
      "C": "to hearing\nA) applaud",
      "D": "hearing\nB) applauding\nC) to applaud 22.I dislike people ______ me what to think.\nD) applause\nA) to tell"
    },
    "answer": "hear"
  },
  {
    "id": "0acaa6dc-77f8-492b-9ab4-9affc92191c6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "“I do hope it’ll make me grow large again, for really\nB) telling\nI’m quite tired ______ such a tiny little thing!” said\nAlice to herself. C) being told\nD) to be telling",
    "options": {
      "A": "to be\n23.I don’t mind ______ at home to look after the children.",
      "B": "of to be",
      "C": "being\nA) to stay",
      "D": "of being\nB) staying"
    },
    "answer": "of being\nB) staying"
  },
  {
    "id": "0b3b721e-c669-4ef2-a625-6f0607851631",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I’m looking forward ______ there in six months’ time.\nC) stay",
    "options": {
      "A": "go D) –",
      "B": "to go 24.Would you like ______ the weekend with us?",
      "C": "going\nA) spending",
      "D": "to going\nB) spend"
    },
    "answer": "to going\nB) spend"
  },
  {
    "id": "27a703bc-bb30-45fe-aaf3-bd843395afa0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "She is very good at ______ problems.\nC) to spending",
    "options": {
      "A": "to solve D) to spend",
      "B": "solving 25.This road is blocked for two miles north and south, so",
      "C": "get rid of I suggest ______ an alternative route if possible.",
      "D": "to get rid of\nA) to using"
    },
    "answer": "solving 25.This road is blocked for two miles north and south, so"
  },
  {
    "id": "4933501c-f0ae-44df-a3bb-e6875c914402",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "711_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Her uncle suggested ______ a job in a bank.\nB) using\nC) use",
    "options": {
      "A": "getting\nD) to use",
      "B": "to get",
      "C": "her to get",
      "D": "her\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-11/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 11"
    },
    "answer": "getting\nD) to use"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c03eefe-2921-42b9-9880-33a0736032c6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Many of the early British settlers in Australia were 8. The French impressionist painters attempted to\ncriminals who were able to avoid ______ by agreeing depict visual impressions and they succeeded ______\nto live on and develop the land there. brilliant results.",
    "options": {
      "A": "be imprisoned A) achieving",
      "B": "to be imprisoned B) achieve",
      "C": "being imprisoned C) to achieve",
      "D": "to imprison D) in achieving"
    },
    "answer": "being imprisoned C) to achieve"
  },
  {
    "id": "5361086d-25a8-4e7f-80f9-c96d6741c3aa",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The environment group hopes ______ the forest to its 9. The company has managed ______ profit this year.\noriginal condition by the end of the decade.",
    "options": {
      "A": "making\nA) restoring",
      "B": "in making\nB) to restore",
      "C": "to make\nC) to be restored",
      "D": "—\nD) having restored"
    },
    "answer": "in making\nB) to restore"
  },
  {
    "id": "5f2cbbbc-3bed-4ee4-8b5e-0260539e65f9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The people in the state failed ______ clean up the\n3. Tom dislikes ______. It’s just terrible! mess that the oil spill had created.",
    "options": {
      "A": "to cook A) to have",
      "B": "Ann to cook B) helping",
      "C": "Ann cook C) to help",
      "D": "Ann’s cooking D) helping hand"
    },
    "answer": "Ann cook C) to help"
  },
  {
    "id": "e7e38dc3-b880-4e2c-894e-55385917b055",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Normally I can’t stand being in a car with drivers who 11.You won’t succeed ______ your car at a profit. It’s far\ntake risks but on this occasion, I couldn’t help ______. too old.",
    "options": {
      "A": "to laugh A) to sell",
      "B": "to be laughing B) in having sold",
      "C": "laughing C) selling",
      "D": "being laughed at D) in selling"
    },
    "answer": "laughing C) selling"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b605abf-43d7-4740-9652-ab71579d94df",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Helen doesn’t mind ______ cigars in the bedroom. 12.At last, after three days, they managed ______ to the\ntop of the mountain.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Tom to smoke\nA) getting",
      "B": "Tom’s smoking\nB) get",
      "C": "Tom smoke\nC) to get",
      "D": "to smoke\nD) —"
    },
    "answer": "Tom’s smoking\nB) get"
  },
  {
    "id": "6fa1dd70-7e4a-49ee-8696-15786098cba6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I can’t stand ______ all the time when I am around\nthem. 13.Driving by a shopping mall on his way home, Steve\nstopped ______ his mother a birthday present.",
    "options": {
      "A": "them fighting\nA) to get",
      "B": "they fighting\nB) to getting",
      "C": "them fight\nC) getting",
      "D": "them to fight\nD) get"
    },
    "answer": "them fighting\nA) to get"
  },
  {
    "id": "e302fb2e-eb35-4330-a62d-304a31c87717",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Instead of collecting art objects, more ordinary\npeople enjoy ______ stamps or coins. 14.– How are the both of you getting on?",
    "options": {
      "A": "to collect – Don’t you know that we’ve stopped ______?",
      "B": "collect\nA) to date",
      "C": "to collecting\nB) dating",
      "D": "collecting\nC) dated\nD) date\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 12"
    },
    "answer": "collecting\nC) dated\nD) date\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 12"
  },
  {
    "id": "ba74d5fc-ae82-4f26-bf3b-211b8b127696",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Fortunately it stopped ______. 21.I regret ______ school at fourteen, it was a big\nmistake.",
    "options": {
      "A": "to rain\nA) to have",
      "B": "raining\nB) to have left",
      "C": "to raining\nC) to leaving",
      "D": "rain\nD) leaving"
    },
    "answer": "raining\nB) to have left"
  },
  {
    "id": "5a7ec63a-337d-4b07-92f2-6583af9126fe",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "When the teacher asked the students ______, they\nkept making noise. 22.That night was terrible, to say the least of it. Jane\nremembers ______ all night through.",
    "options": {
      "A": "stop talking\nA) to pray",
      "B": "to stop to talk\nB) saying prayers",
      "C": "stopping talking\nC) to say prayers",
      "D": "to stop talking\nD) say prayers"
    },
    "answer": "to stop talking\nD) say prayers"
  },
  {
    "id": "51a89cc2-8b2f-4c03-9b7e-f1d667a97e82",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Oh, dear! I forgot ______ the soap.\n23.The Oscar winner was so happy to receive the",
    "options": {
      "A": "buying highest honour of her profession that she nearly cried\nduring her acceptance speech. Don’t forget ______ it",
      "B": "buy\nin your report.",
      "C": "to buy",
      "D": "having bought A) writing"
    },
    "answer": "to buy"
  },
  {
    "id": "6267fe0d-a8f1-4580-a15a-eb51213c00c3",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I remember ______ at the school gates with my B) to write\nmother on my first day there. C) on writing\nD) write",
    "options": {
      "A": "to have arrived\n24.You must remember ______ Mr Lewis from the station",
      "B": "to arrive\ntomorrow.",
      "C": "arriving",
      "D": "to be arrived A) fetching"
    },
    "answer": "arriving"
  },
  {
    "id": "6787e797-ce3e-4cac-8a97-982fe3dc9256",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I remember ______ my first bicycle, the feeling of B) fetch\ndelight still being fresh in mind. C) to have fetched\nD) to fetch",
    "options": {
      "A": "to buy\n25.I’ll never forget ______ the Queen on that bright day",
      "B": "being bought by\nin 1974.",
      "C": "bought",
      "D": "buying A) meeting"
    },
    "answer": "buying A) meeting"
  },
  {
    "id": "bc6a18c1-9b75-4e97-9eea-ceefed85fa92",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "712_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Oh, I forgot ______ the present for my sweet girl! B) to meet\nC) being met",
    "options": {
      "A": "buying\nD) to be met",
      "B": "to buy",
      "C": "to buying",
      "D": "buy\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-12/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 12"
    },
    "answer": "to buy"
  },
  {
    "id": "75f2fb3a-8bec-4186-8ee5-2175bec1fafd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I ______ to have an old Rolls-Royce. 8. I never wore tight jeans before, but now I ______\nthem. It’s so stylish!",
    "options": {
      "A": "used\nA) am used to wear",
      "B": "would\nB) am used to wearing",
      "C": "was used\nC) used to wear",
      "D": "got used\nD) accustomed to wear"
    },
    "answer": "used\nA) am used to wear"
  },
  {
    "id": "59893c39-ef3f-44b5-ad98-16b34137f977",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "When fashion changed I ______ to wearing short\nskirts. 9. When we were little, we went to school in the sea.\nThe master was an old Turtle - we ______ call him",
    "options": {
      "A": "didn’t use Tortoise.",
      "B": "used not\nA) were used to",
      "C": "couldn’t get used\nB) used to",
      "D": "can’t get used\nC) got used to"
    },
    "answer": "couldn’t get used\nB) used to"
  },
  {
    "id": "2621183f-e422-4ddf-81e8-21ddec741a70",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Unfortunately we are less well-off now than we\nD) would to\n______.\n10.In earlier times, someone ______ home and was able",
    "options": {
      "A": "got used to be to take proper care of the pets.",
      "B": "get used to being\nA) has stayed",
      "C": "used to be\nB) used to stay",
      "D": "would be\nC) was used to stay"
    },
    "answer": "used to be\nB) used to stay"
  },
  {
    "id": "c9ecb901-987d-4a51-91b2-5c0be6f7c486",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "From now on, we won’t be able to go out as much as\nD) accustomed to stay\nwe ______.\n11.Before the train was invented people ______ travel",
    "options": {
      "A": "were to mostly by horse.",
      "B": "used to being\nA) were used to",
      "C": "used to\nB) got used to",
      "D": "get used to\nC) used"
    },
    "answer": "used to\nB) got used to"
  },
  {
    "id": "557d609f-d04d-44ff-82cb-dff31669fafc",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "In those days, trains ______ to have a guard in the last\nD) used to\ncarriage.\n12.Sean’s ______ with difficult kids.",
    "options": {
      "A": "used\nA) used to dealing",
      "B": "were used\nB) used to deal",
      "C": "got used\nC) got used to deal",
      "D": "would\nD) used"
    },
    "answer": "used\nA) used to dealing"
  },
  {
    "id": "a2edb78f-7a57-4229-a5f6-b25cdad479a7",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I always buy tight jeans. I ______ them loose.\n13.I ______ sleeping on the floor.",
    "options": {
      "A": "can’t use to wear\nA) never used to",
      "B": "didn’t used to wear\nB) never be used to",
      "C": "can’t get used to wear\nC) will never get used to",
      "D": "can’t get used to wearing\nD) will never get used"
    },
    "answer": "can’t get used to wearing\nD) will never get used"
  },
  {
    "id": "14e852e8-5dd2-4f63-889d-3073cf2e8b77",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Jeans ______ just work clothes but then they began to\nappear on movie stars. 14.Ancient people ______ to believe that the earth was\nflat.",
    "options": {
      "A": "are used to being\nA) used",
      "B": "were used to being\nB) got used",
      "C": "got used to be\nC) were used",
      "D": "used to be\nD) was used\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 14"
    },
    "answer": "used to be\nD) was used\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 14"
  },
  {
    "id": "e8683d13-57c3-45d9-bc6d-563f3d4de55e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I’m not sure where to turn. I ______ driving this way. 21.I used to write my letters by hand, but now ______ I\ntyping them.",
    "options": {
      "A": "am used to\nA) got used",
      "B": "am not used to\nB) got used to",
      "C": "used to\nC) would",
      "D": "didn’t use to\nD) used to"
    },
    "answer": "am not used to\nB) got used to"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5a10961-79f1-4b26-bed3-35c3fc22465e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Although I come from Russia I ______ driving in\nLondon. 22.I ______ to belong to a cycling club when I was young.",
    "options": {
      "A": "am used to\nA) would",
      "B": "used to\nB) got used",
      "C": "am used\nC) was used",
      "D": "got used\nD) used"
    },
    "answer": "am used to\nA) would"
  },
  {
    "id": "45b17166-1671-4802-b0db-9ad1d349bd31",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I ______ be shy when I was younger.\n23.I used to travel to work by train, but the fares got too",
    "options": {
      "A": "am used dear so now I ______ coming to work on my bicycle.",
      "B": "am used to\nA) would",
      "C": "used to\nB) got used",
      "D": "was used to\nC) am used to"
    },
    "answer": "used to\nB) got used"
  },
  {
    "id": "c13fe957-6eac-467b-a152-8de6040ddfc4",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "In the 19th century people ______ bigger families.\nD) used",
    "options": {
      "A": "have 24.As a child, I ______ science fiction, and my mind was\nfull of strange images.",
      "B": "are used to having",
      "C": "used to have\nA) have been reading",
      "D": "used to having\nB) had been reading"
    },
    "answer": "used to have\nA) have been reading"
  },
  {
    "id": "ffcb4a45-8358-4ca9-94a5-116fa6a5e048",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Aren’t you ______ this far? It’s only 5 miles. C) used to read\nD) was used to read",
    "options": {
      "A": "use to walk\n25.When I was a boy, I ______ to visit my aunts in the",
      "B": "used to walking\ncountry.",
      "C": "used to walk",
      "D": "got used to walking A) used"
    },
    "answer": "used to walking\ncountry."
  },
  {
    "id": "4c711a9e-a7a0-4893-918c-823019ab1a1f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "714_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "When we were children we ______ go skating every B) would\nwinter. C) got used\nD) was used",
    "options": {
      "A": "use to",
      "B": "were used to",
      "C": "used to",
      "D": "am used to\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-14/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 14"
    },
    "answer": "used to"
  },
  {
    "id": "3b61f0d6-72b5-4b00-b8be-b3db6f89fd39",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Anorexia Nervosa is a disease typical for young 8. I hear you’ve been to Patagonia. That trip ______ been\nwomen who believe that they ______ be as thin as the interesting.\nmodels in the fashion magazines.",
    "options": {
      "A": "ought\nA) have got",
      "B": "must\nB) obliged",
      "C": "must have\nC) could",
      "D": "had\nD) must"
    },
    "answer": "had\nD) must"
  },
  {
    "id": "eb1cbe69-f767-45b1-aeb4-cf089d05fa5d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I think they ______ consult a doctor as soon as\n2. The coach has very strict rules about exercise: all possible. It can be too late.\nstudents ______ exercise at least three times a week.",
    "options": {
      "A": "might\nA) have to",
      "B": "can\nB) should",
      "C": "ought\nC) ought",
      "D": "must\nD) would"
    },
    "answer": "must\nD) would"
  },
  {
    "id": "50d2f9b2-77b5-49d5-b462-daa1db4fede7",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "If she doesn’t buy a ticket, she ______ go to the\n3. She ______ write the whole exercise. Ten sentences theatre tomorrow.\nare enough.",
    "options": {
      "A": "won’t be able\nA) needs to",
      "B": "won’t be permitted\nB) need",
      "C": "can’t\nC) needn’t",
      "D": "won’t be allowed\nD) mustn’t"
    },
    "answer": "can’t\nC) needn’t"
  },
  {
    "id": "980f6490-053f-4cbe-a3ed-03bc2563d23d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "It was a nice evening, but I’m afraid I ______ Aunt\n4. The sign ‘Overtaking forbidden’ means that you Mary today more than usual.\n______ overtake.",
    "options": {
      "A": "might annoy\nA) are allowed to",
      "B": "could annoy\nB) aren’t allowed to",
      "C": "might have annoyed\nC) don’t have",
      "D": "could be annoying\nD) have to"
    },
    "answer": "could annoy\nB) aren’t allowed to"
  },
  {
    "id": "fe75dc3b-da1f-4a7a-9ae4-6e6fde8057a5",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "It’s rained a lot, so we ______ water the garden.\n5. Cold sufferers should stay at home, not only for their\nown health but because they ______ endanger the",
    "options": {
      "A": "don’t need\nhealth of their co-workers.",
      "B": "don’t have",
      "C": "needn’t\nA) must",
      "D": "need\nB) have to\nC) might 13.You ______ pay now – tomorrow’s OK.\nD) are supposed to\nA) needn’t"
    },
    "answer": "needn’t\nA) must"
  },
  {
    "id": "de7d3d59-a678-497a-9588-59d608da914b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Although some desert plants can survive without\nB) must\nwater, most plants and all animals ______ have food\nin order to live. C) don’t need\nD) don’t have",
    "options": {
      "A": "should\n14.People ______ to drive more carefully.",
      "B": "must",
      "C": "ought A) should",
      "D": "have got B) ought"
    },
    "answer": "must"
  },
  {
    "id": "e0cd8da8-dcde-4d85-93f8-e6ef4757bebe",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "It is generally agreed that when you travel in C) must\ncountries other than your own, you ______ conform to D) are allowed\nthe local customs as much as possible.\n15.______ to work extra?",
    "options": {
      "A": "could\nA) Have I",
      "B": "might\nB) Do I have",
      "C": "ought\nC) Need I",
      "D": "should\nD) Must I\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 15"
    },
    "answer": "should\nD) Must I\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 15"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c837549-b682-4bd8-9ad6-73d9840e9bc1",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I ______ to speak English fluently by the end of the 21.The sign ‘Non-Members Welcome’ means that you\nyear. ______ be a member to get in.",
    "options": {
      "A": "will be allowed A) are allowed to",
      "B": "could B) are not allowed to",
      "C": "will be able C) have to",
      "D": "can D) don’t have to"
    },
    "answer": "will be able C) have to"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a3b0403-e6c2-48a9-a2e2-428e44a07cc1",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Residents ______ hang washing out of the windows. 22.Students ______ register at the tutorial office in the\nIt’s prohibited. first week of term. It’s our demand.",
    "options": {
      "A": "should A) must to",
      "B": "don’t have to B) ought",
      "C": "must C) may",
      "D": "must not D) must"
    },
    "answer": "must not D) must"
  },
  {
    "id": "3c40bb1d-779a-4825-9433-f5f1855aef3a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "If you like this scarf, you ______ find it at any shop. 23.They knelt in front of the child who ______ one day\nrule all England.",
    "options": {
      "A": "must\nA) were to",
      "B": "should\nB) would",
      "C": "ought to\nC) hadn’t to",
      "D": "can\nD) may not 19.I ______ work tomorrow. It is a good opportunity to go\nto the country. 24.People really ______ hard in those days.\nA) will have A) had to work\nB) won’t have to B) must work\nC) am allowed C) may work\nD) am not allowed D) was to"
    },
    "answer": "can\nD) may not 19.I ______ work tomorrow. It is a good opportunity to go\nto the country. 24.People really ______ hard in those days.\nA) will have A) had to work\nB) won’t have to B) must work\nC) am allowed C) may work\nD) am not allowed D) was to"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a33586b-a013-4c53-a70b-d0e8a4eb7645",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "715_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The sign ‘Do not bring pet animals’ means that you 25.There’s the phone. I’ll get it. That ______ be Tony.\n______ bring pet animals.",
    "options": {
      "A": "has to\nA) are allowed to",
      "B": "must\nB) aren’t allowed to",
      "C": "ought\nC) have to",
      "D": "is to\nD) don’t have to\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-15/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 15"
    },
    "answer": "must\nB) aren’t allowed to"
  },
  {
    "id": "a29c5788-660f-4285-83be-f0a0b34fa6fa",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "What ______ is that it’s not right to gossip. 9. And yet I wish ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "do I think about this news A) I could you show our cat Dinah to",
      "B": "I think about this news B) I could our cat Dinah show to you",
      "C": "think I about the news C) our cat Dinah could you show to",
      "D": "don’t I think of the news D) I could show you our cat Dinah"
    },
    "answer": "I think about this news B) I could our cat Dinah show to you"
  },
  {
    "id": "c093e23b-c2ce-4fcd-9b26-28d09d373c3e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ is not my concern. 10.Then it doesn’t matter ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "Where is on earth Charlie now A) which way you go.",
      "B": "Where on earth is Charlie now B) which way do you go?",
      "C": "Where on earth Charlie is now C) which you go way.",
      "D": "Where is Charlie now D) which way you go?"
    },
    "answer": "Where on earth Charlie is now C) which you go way."
  },
  {
    "id": "330e3690-fae1-4dc9-a974-a3fa8ee0045a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ doesn’t matter at this point. 11.I asked ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "When the money stolen was A) where were the president and his wife staying?",
      "B": "When did they steal the money B) where were the president and his wife staying.",
      "C": "When the money was stolen C) what hotel were the president and his wife",
      "D": "When was the money stolen staying."
    },
    "answer": "When the money was stolen C) what hotel were the president and his wife"
  },
  {
    "id": "4fe91db4-f026-4633-8da3-d62b04b580df",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I’m often asked ______. D) what hotel the president and his wife were staying\nat.",
    "options": {
      "A": "what students can do to become part of a team\n12.He wanted to know ______",
      "B": "what can students do to become part of a team",
      "C": "what can do students to become part of a team A) when could I start.",
      "D": "what to become part of a team can students do B) when I could start?"
    },
    "answer": "what students can do to become part of a team\n12.He wanted to know ______"
  },
  {
    "id": "7528f418-08d4-4d0b-ac5f-cd328074d799",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ is none of my business. C) what time could I start at.\nD) what time I could start at.",
    "options": {
      "A": "What did the boss tell her\n13.She asked me if ______",
      "B": "What the boss did her tell",
      "C": "What her told the boss A) I like the drink?",
      "D": "What the boss told her B) I would like the drink."
    },
    "answer": "What the boss told her B) I would like the drink."
  },
  {
    "id": "f6e5730f-bd07-468c-b3e3-2763ba7fe2e9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "When ______ does not interest me. C) the drinks would like me.\nD) what would the drinks like?",
    "options": {
      "A": "are they going to arrest Charlie\n14.I asked ______ something.",
      "B": "Charlie is going to be arrested",
      "C": "is Charlie going to be arrested A) what he had told me",
      "D": "is Charlie going to arrest them B) whether he had told me"
    },
    "answer": "Charlie is going to be arrested"
  },
  {
    "id": "0fc7f063-9687-4b99-8874-38bb55ed4b8d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Why ______ C) if had he told me\nD) had he told me",
    "options": {
      "A": "do people laugh at one joke but not another\n15.I don’t know ______\ndepends on many factors.",
      "B": "people laugh at one joke but not another depends A) why did he tell this story to everybody?\non many factors. B) why was this story told to everybody?",
      "C": "people laugh at one joke but not another depends C) why everybody was told this story?\non many factors?",
      "D": "why he told this story to everybody.\nD) do people laugh at one joke but not another 16.I asked what ______\ndepends on many factors.\nA) Peter’s address was?"
    },
    "answer": "people laugh at one joke but not another depends A) why did he tell this story to everybody?\non many factors. B) why was this story told to everybody?"
  },
  {
    "id": "a398d512-fb42-46d5-a6e6-aae25b17082f",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Everybody all over the world loves what ______\nB) Peter’s address was.",
    "options": {
      "A": "does a good joke do. C) was Peter’s address?",
      "B": "does a good joke do? D) address was Peter’s?",
      "C": "a good joke does?",
      "D": "a good joke does.\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 16"
    },
    "answer": "a good joke does.\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 16"
  },
  {
    "id": "ca3344ee-a39d-44bc-a7b5-fdeafa3c820a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I asked: “______” 22.The government has announced ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Do you have this costume in size 8? A) will the taxes be raised",
      "B": "If they had that costume in size 8. B) taxes that would be raised",
      "C": "Whether they had that costume in size 8. C) that taxes will be raised",
      "D": "Did they have that costume in size 8? D) that there will taxes be raised"
    },
    "answer": "Do you have this costume in size 8? A) will the taxes be raised"
  },
  {
    "id": "fb75901f-0f21-4e02-983d-93278596e2a9",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I wondered ______ 23.He’s got a job in a new firm, ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "where was the bus station. A) where don’t they work such long hours",
      "B": "where the bus station was. B) there don’t they work such long hours",
      "C": "where was the bus station? C) such long hours don’t they work there",
      "D": "where the bus station was? D) where they don’t work such long hours"
    },
    "answer": "where the bus station was. B) there don’t they work such long hours"
  },
  {
    "id": "a3d0b4a2-6765-4d5e-9d5b-fe7220d24f4d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "You wanted to know if ______ 24.Nobody told me why ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "I had met George Lamb. A) did I have to sign the paper?",
      "B": "I had met George Lamb? B) I had to sign the paper?",
      "C": "had I met George Lamb. C) didn’t I have the paper signed.",
      "D": "had I met George Lamb? D) I had to sign the paper."
    },
    "answer": "I had met George Lamb. A) did I have to sign the paper?"
  },
  {
    "id": "452e4d97-46df-48e6-b025-398a90121cf2",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The driver asked ______ 25.I’m surprised at ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "if I want to the town centre. A) how fast can she run?",
      "B": "whether I wanted to the town centre. B) how fast can she run.",
      "C": "whether I wanted to the town centre? C) how fast she can run.",
      "D": "the town centre if I wanted. D) can she run fast at all?"
    },
    "answer": "whether I wanted to the town centre. B) how fast can she run."
  },
  {
    "id": "aefe0810-667d-4639-83b4-4f62a5f6b3a6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "716_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "How ______",
    "options": {
      "A": "you get there is your problem?",
      "B": "do you get there is your problem .",
      "C": "you get there is your problem.",
      "D": "you get there your problem?\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-16/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 16"
    },
    "answer": "you get there is your problem."
  },
  {
    "id": "ab7b483a-d023-41fe-ac5e-3cccaa2efd4d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Concepts of modem nursing were founded by 8. ______ we need is a big fridge.\nFlorence Nightingale, an English nurse ______ to the\ncare of the sick and the war-wounded.",
    "options": {
      "A": "That",
      "B": "Who\nA) which dedicated her life",
      "C": "Whom\nB) which life was dedicated",
      "D": "What\nC) whose life was dedicated"
    },
    "answer": "Whom\nB) which life was dedicated"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e68a66c-66b8-49cc-bb06-8fd97f8b9195",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Martin’s garage, ______ the car had been taken to,\nD) that life was dedicated\nwas not far away.\n2. I have had many teachers ______ I have admired\ngreatly.",
    "options": {
      "A": "what",
      "B": "who\nA) whose",
      "C": "whom\nB) whom",
      "D": "where\nC) which"
    },
    "answer": "where\nC) which"
  },
  {
    "id": "c0729a51-6509-4580-90e4-d8a8217902b1",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The Olympic Games, ______ in 776 B.C., did not\nD) what\ninclude women participants until 1912.\n3. It is not surprising that the person ______ influenced\nmy life the most was a teacher.",
    "options": {
      "A": "who first played",
      "B": "first played\nA) who",
      "C": "that they were first played\nB) which",
      "D": "they were first played\nC) —"
    },
    "answer": "first played\nA) who"
  },
  {
    "id": "92fc9e3c-5c2c-4877-998f-26bcf56df596",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "They gave me ______ I asked for.\nD) whose\n4. Few visitors to Disney World in Florida know that",
    "options": {
      "A": "that\nmuch of its electrical power comes from the energy",
      "B": "what\n______ by burning its own garbage.",
      "C": "which\nA) that produces",
      "D": "when\nB) what is produce 12.There’s the man ______ took your coat.\nC) which it is produced\nA) which\nD) it produces\nB) who"
    },
    "answer": "what\n______ by burning its own garbage."
  },
  {
    "id": "f3092f15-289a-4a00-9b05-839c995d16dc",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Tulips, ______ into Holland in 1554, were quickly and\nhighly valued, and by the 1630s they became the C) —\nobjects of wild financial speculation in Europe. D) whom\n13.It’s certain to be a good game, ______ wins.",
    "options": {
      "A": "which introduced",
      "B": "that they were introduced A) whichever",
      "C": "which introduced them B) whatever",
      "D": "introduced C) however"
    },
    "answer": "introduced C) however"
  },
  {
    "id": "1a8b3e83-0a92-497f-ad19-65c7a9a3541e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Cork, the second-largest city in Ireland, is the site of D) whoever\nmany industries, ______ automobile manufacturing\n14.The people in Canada were very friendly ______ we\nand whiskey distilling.\nwent.",
    "options": {
      "A": "two of whom are\nA) whatever",
      "B": "which two are\nB) however",
      "C": "two of which are\nC) wherever",
      "D": "two of that are\nD) when"
    },
    "answer": "two of which are\nC) wherever"
  },
  {
    "id": "a5c297cf-e090-486f-82d0-076de579e9e6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Because of the success ______ I had in this class, I\n15.The dentist had to pull out two of my teeth, ______\nbecame more confident and at ease.\nwas a real pity.",
    "options": {
      "A": "—\nA) that",
      "B": "whose\nB) what",
      "C": "what\nC) which",
      "D": "whom\nD) —\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 17"
    },
    "answer": "—\nA) that"
  },
  {
    "id": "a799ef53-f162-40f0-8fbf-7c994038cb56",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I’ll give you my address and phone number but I 21.______ I’d like most is a home computer.\nneed something ______.",
    "options": {
      "A": "That\nA) I can write",
      "B": "Which\nB) that I can write",
      "C": "What\nC) I can write on",
      "D": "Who\nD) what I can write on"
    },
    "answer": "What\nC) I can write on"
  },
  {
    "id": "aa0346ba-4a12-45a1-a5a0-b94f9b1e4e26",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Sergeant Brown, ______ was very polite.\n17.She is lucky, ______ much she eats, she never gets\nfat.",
    "options": {
      "A": "whom I showed my license,",
      "B": "which I showed my license to\nA) whatever",
      "C": "to what I showed my license\nB) however",
      "D": "who to I showed my license\nC) whoever"
    },
    "answer": "whom I showed my license,"
  },
  {
    "id": "19fbd7a7-91d7-460a-8cb7-586410698dfe",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Where is the man ______ I saw this morning?\nD) whenever\n18.I liked ______ you said at the meeting very much.",
    "options": {
      "A": "who",
      "B": "this\nA) which",
      "C": "whose\nB) what",
      "D": "which\nC) that"
    },
    "answer": "who"
  },
  {
    "id": "9e2b66b7-2d09-4cab-8777-f10de402b056",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "There is the driver ______ overtook us five minutes\nD) than\nago.\n19.Where is the book ______ I bought this morning?",
    "options": {
      "A": "whom\nA) whose",
      "B": "whose\nB) what",
      "C": "which\nC) that",
      "D": "who\nD) whom"
    },
    "answer": "who\nD) whom"
  },
  {
    "id": "2370d0b1-40af-45b9-b390-0eb62f88818c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "717_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "He is a man ______ falls a heavy responsibility.\n20.______ caused the accident, nobody knows.",
    "options": {
      "A": "on his shoulders\nA) Which",
      "B": "who\nB) What",
      "C": "whose shoulders\nC) That",
      "D": "on whom\nD) Whichever\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 17"
    },
    "answer": "on whom\nD) Whichever\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-17/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 17"
  },
  {
    "id": "6a295aa2-2650-4ff9-901a-f4eda8bd933c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "What ______ 8. ______ him, Andrey or Andrew?",
    "options": {
      "A": "effect does the speed of telling the joke have on A) What did you call\nits success or failure.",
      "B": "Call\nB) does the speed of telling the joke effect have on",
      "C": "What you called\nits success or failure.",
      "D": "How you called\nC) effect does the speed of telling the joke have on 9. ______ do you wish that you had married, then?\nits success or failure?\nD) does the speed of telling the joke effect have on A) Why\nits success or failure? B) Whose\nC) Which"
    },
    "answer": "What you called\nits success or failure."
  },
  {
    "id": "b98cfb65-fdd3-41a3-a847-cbef38a01743",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Why ______\nD) Who",
    "options": {
      "A": "you laughed at the last joke that you heard. 10.“ Don’t touch that !”",
      "B": "did you laugh at the last joke that you heard.\n“ Why ______?”",
      "C": "did you laugh at the last joke that you heard?",
      "D": "you laughed at the last joke that you heard?\nA) shouldn’t I"
    },
    "answer": "did you laugh at the last joke that you heard?"
  },
  {
    "id": "1063a153-c773-452a-b14c-14f332f642c0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ they live in? B) to keep it untouched\nC) not to touch it",
    "options": {
      "A": "Who’s house do you say\nD) should I",
      "B": "Whose house you say\n11.Ann’s very unhappy. But ______ care?!",
      "C": "Whose house do",
      "D": "Who’s house do\nA) why have I to"
    },
    "answer": "Whose house do"
  },
  {
    "id": "410654d0-35a2-4e7e-87c1-15ac37af5c29",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ you wanted for your birthday? B) why not to forget of the\nC) why should I",
    "options": {
      "A": "Which did you say\nD) how should I",
      "B": "Whose did you say\n12.Which ______ more – the blue one or the grey one?",
      "C": "What did you say",
      "D": "What you said\nA) did cost"
    },
    "answer": "What did you say"
  },
  {
    "id": "187c8180-b6fc-4168-abd4-9ea5fc492fe4",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "What ______ B) does cost\nC) costs",
    "options": {
      "A": "the factors are that make a joke funny to\nD) have cost\nsomeone?\n13.How many people ______ in your office?",
      "B": "are the factors that make a joke funny to\nsomeone.\nA) did work",
      "C": "are the factors that make a joke funny to\nB) did use to work\nsomeone?\nC) work",
      "D": "the factors are that make a joke funny to\nD) do work\nsomeone."
    },
    "answer": "are the factors that make a joke funny to\nB) did use to work\nsomeone?\nC) work"
  },
  {
    "id": "61983199-d11d-4e14-b47d-f9ae67718676",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "What most ______ help, your textbook or your\n6. Why ______ go out for a meal tonight? dictionary?",
    "options": {
      "A": "we don’t A) give you",
      "B": "do B) do you give",
      "C": "don’t we C) does you give",
      "D": "we D) gives you"
    },
    "answer": "we D) gives you"
  },
  {
    "id": "4d136d07-bdae-4cbe-983d-2498b1e7cf69",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ today? 15.______ do you think we should wait?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Is William feeling some better A) How much",
      "B": "Don’t you think William is feeling some better B) How so far",
      "C": "Is William feeling any better C) How long",
      "D": "Is William feeling something at all D) How many\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 18"
    },
    "answer": "Is William feeling any better C) How long"
  },
  {
    "id": "f45f8117-d2ac-4f88-ae37-27eeada12bfd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ time to go to London this weekend ? 21.______ are you looking after?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Do you have got A) Why",
      "B": "Have you got B) How",
      "C": "Do you have to C) Where",
      "D": "Don’t you have got D) Who"
    },
    "answer": "Have you got B) How"
  },
  {
    "id": "59dd7b20-fe8c-4e06-bc73-affffc94aa06",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "\"It was a terrible party\" 22.– What ______? Is he a writer?\n\" ______\"",
    "options": {
      "A": "has Ben done",
      "B": "does Ben do\nA) Was it as terrible party?",
      "C": "is Ben doing\nB) Was it so?",
      "D": "Ben likes\nC) Did it?"
    },
    "answer": "Ben likes\nC) Did it?"
  },
  {
    "id": "16988b74-a8c5-4a65-8a80-744c352c6ea0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ are those men laughing at?\nD) Was it?\n18.– I’ve never seen Ann. What ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Why",
      "B": "Where\n– She is very pretty.",
      "C": "Whose\nA) is she doing",
      "D": "What\nB) is she 24.– ______\nC) does she do\n– Much better now.\nD) is she like"
    },
    "answer": "What\nB) is she 24.– ______\nC) does she do\n– Much better now.\nD) is she like"
  },
  {
    "id": "daf70581-6f9c-49ca-823c-9e7f7315a40c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "– What ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "How your school is?",
      "B": "How’s your school.\n– He is a writer.",
      "C": "What your school is like?\nA) has Ben done",
      "D": "How are you getting on at school?\nB) does Ben do 25.– ______?\nC) is Ben doing\n– Short, dark and cheerful-looking.\nD) Ben likes"
    },
    "answer": "How’s your school.\n– He is a writer."
  },
  {
    "id": "c181a804-599b-4f04-8155-cc651196d97e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "718_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "– ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "How’s your sister",
      "B": "How does she seem today\n– Much better now.",
      "C": "What does your sister look like\nA) What does Helen do",
      "D": "What is your sister\nB) Who is Helen\nC) How is Helen getting on\nD) What is Helen\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-18/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 18"
    },
    "answer": "What does your sister look like\nA) What does Helen do"
  },
  {
    "id": "c2dc8d22-3d77-4081-b77a-efae1f41979c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "We know nothing of others and little of ourselves, 9. You don’t happen to know how this computer works,\n______? ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "do we A) are you",
      "B": "don’t we B) don’t you",
      "C": "isn’t it C) do you",
      "D": "are we D) isn’t it"
    },
    "answer": "do we A) are you"
  },
  {
    "id": "1215a037-1c4e-4e98-a228-51bd435ff38a",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "George can’t have noticed it, ______? 10.Don’t drive too fast, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "can he A) shall you",
      "B": "has he B) do you",
      "C": "have he C) will you",
      "D": "did he D) can you"
    },
    "answer": "can he A) shall you"
  },
  {
    "id": "71fdf110-eb4e-415f-8863-93848c9b957e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "We hardly know who invented the wheel, ______? 11.“Let the jury consider their verdict, ______?” the King\nsaid, for about the twentieth time that day.",
    "options": {
      "A": "didn’t he\nA) shall we",
      "B": "did he\nB) will you",
      "C": "don’t we\nC) can you",
      "D": "do we\nD) don’t you"
    },
    "answer": "do we\nD) don’t you"
  },
  {
    "id": "df407c19-1340-4843-b8cf-3d3c6c2f2d08",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Nothing can be changed, ______?\n12.You’re never happy, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "can’t it\nA) are you",
      "B": "can it\nB) aren’t you",
      "C": "cannot it\nC) weren’t you",
      "D": "isn’t it\nD) won’t you"
    },
    "answer": "can it\nB) aren’t you"
  },
  {
    "id": "a1344de9-fcb2-4709-905b-3cb56e34280c",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Don’t leave anything behind, ______?\n13.Nobody phoned, ______ they?",
    "options": {
      "A": "do you\nA) didn’t",
      "B": "will you\nB) did not",
      "C": "don’t you\nC) did",
      "D": "can you\nD) haven’t"
    },
    "answer": "will you\nB) did not"
  },
  {
    "id": "807c4bdc-c259-4752-b6cf-c2e7148f4353",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Let’s have a drink, ______?\n14.Cathy’s still got curly hair, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "shall we\nA) doesn’t she",
      "B": "shan’t we\nB) does she",
      "C": "won’t we\nC) hasn’t she",
      "D": "don’t we\nD) has she"
    },
    "answer": "shall we\nA) doesn’t she"
  },
  {
    "id": "dcba9fcb-37bd-43c9-b7bb-9b3b87ff8105",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Let’s go to London next weekend, ______?\n15.That’s the law, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "won’t we\nA) is it",
      "B": "shall we\nB) isn’t it",
      "C": "don’t we\nC) is that",
      "D": "shall we not\nD) isn’t there"
    },
    "answer": "shall we\nB) isn’t it"
  },
  {
    "id": "2fbe9c59-e19d-4bb5-931a-1a565b0a85c0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Answer the phone for me, ______?\n16.I’m cooking tonight, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "don’t you\nA) am not I",
      "B": "shall you\nB) isn’t it",
      "C": "do you\nC) aren’t I",
      "D": "will you\nD) am I\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 19"
    },
    "answer": "will you\nD) am I\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 19"
  },
  {
    "id": "21d229d1-eb7a-4909-a064-5f3932d6af52",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Nice day, ______? 22.I’m causing you a lot of trouble, Doctor, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "is it A) aren’t I",
      "B": "isn’t it B) am I",
      "C": "is that C) am not I",
      "D": "isn’t that D) shall I"
    },
    "answer": "isn’t it B) am I"
  },
  {
    "id": "f102d8df-73ed-4b48-a7d6-c1971037429d",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "There’s a light out there, ______? 23.Catholics have to go to church on Sundays, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "isn’t it A) haven’t they",
      "B": "is it B) hasn’t they",
      "C": "isn’t there C) don’t they",
      "D": "is there D) shouldn’t they"
    },
    "answer": "isn’t there C) don’t they"
  },
  {
    "id": "3256d278-93d1-4381-b562-df8fd97f0ee1",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "You never say what you’re thinking, ______ you? 24.I needn’t take the medicine, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "don’t A) do I",
      "B": "aren’t B) need I",
      "C": "are C) needn’t I",
      "D": "do D) don’t I"
    },
    "answer": "do D) don’t I"
  },
  {
    "id": "39a9b81c-0083-493c-b365-80db88cd0950",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I’m looking better today, Doctor, ______ I? 25.Richard's bought a new bike, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "amn’t A) does he",
      "B": "am B) did he",
      "C": "don’t C) has he",
      "D": "aren’t D) hasn't he"
    },
    "answer": "aren’t D) hasn't he"
  },
  {
    "id": "83535c11-d62f-4d43-8784-ef3f0dc8cf47",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "719_self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "You have to wear a tie at work, ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "do you",
      "B": "haven’t you",
      "C": "aren’t you",
      "D": "don’t you\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 19"
    },
    "answer": "don’t you\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-test-your-english-grammar-part-19/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Test Your English Grammar Part 19"
  },
  {
    "id": "aaf9c0d5-0981-4a7e-9084-8db4985b6a3e",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "She’s ______ mother of my best friend. 9. – ______?",
    "options": {
      "A": "a – Tall, good-looking, a bit shy.",
      "B": "his\nA) What’s Jim like",
      "C": "that\nB) How does he look today",
      "D": "the\nC) What is Jim"
    },
    "answer": "the\nC) What is Jim"
  },
  {
    "id": "94091deb-e236-4738-8e52-5046c66cd4e0",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ you do, don’t tell Harry that we’ve lost his\nD) How is Jim\ncamera.\n10.Let’s have a party, ______ we ?",
    "options": {
      "A": "Anything\nA) shall",
      "B": "What\nB) let",
      "C": "Whatever\nC) let not",
      "D": "It’s better\nD) will"
    },
    "answer": "Whatever\nC) let not"
  },
  {
    "id": "1f42442f-dddf-454b-b007-90122388f8b7",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "The fish is ______ the meat.\n11.______ some problems.",
    "options": {
      "A": "as tasty as\nA) There seems to be",
      "B": "so tasty as\nB) It seems to be",
      "C": "more tasty\nC) It seem to be",
      "D": "most tasty\nD) There seem to be"
    },
    "answer": "as tasty as\nA) There seems to be"
  },
  {
    "id": "1e32c95f-9b3f-4df9-9343-6e6158ffd6ba",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "______ is no concern of mine.\n12.If he had not been a film-star, he ______ the President",
    "options": {
      "A": "What will happen to Charlie of the US.",
      "B": "What will they do with Charlie\nA) wasn’t",
      "C": "What to Charlie will happen\nB) could be",
      "D": "What will Charlie do with them\nC) wouldn’t be"
    },
    "answer": "What will happen to Charlie of the US."
  },
  {
    "id": "3b3c2b06-973c-4294-bf35-78efa58cd641",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "In a few years, computers ______ think better than we\nD) wouldn’t have become\ndo.\n13.Would you like ______ racing at the weekend?",
    "options": {
      "A": "can\nA) going",
      "B": "will be allowed to\nB) to going",
      "C": "will be able to\nC) go",
      "D": "shall be able\nD) to go"
    },
    "answer": "will be able to\nC) go"
  },
  {
    "id": "4c2ef071-c2d6-470f-a9ab-301f55b41fe6",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Don’t touch the book. It ______ to me.\n14.Tom Sawyer was able to make ______ by pretending",
    "options": {
      "A": "is belonging that the work was a specific privilege.",
      "B": "doesn’t belong\nA) his friends painting the fence",
      "C": "belonged\nB) his friends to paint the fence",
      "D": "is always belonging\nC) his friends paint the fence"
    },
    "answer": "doesn’t belong\nA) his friends painting the fence"
  },
  {
    "id": "4fb6372c-e3c5-4cec-89c5-2b259f1389dd",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I ______ with children before, so I know what to expect\nD) the fence paint his friends\nin my new job.\n15.Before photography ______, people had their pictures",
    "options": {
      "A": "have worked painted.",
      "B": "worked\nA) had invented",
      "C": "was worked\nB) was inventing",
      "D": "work\nC) was invented"
    },
    "answer": "have worked painted."
  },
  {
    "id": "aa150518-1a2a-4d83-8ba8-3b2f5e129bba",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "She’s been floating on the air ______ the day of her\nD) inventing\nengagement.",
    "options": {
      "A": "since",
      "B": "when",
      "C": "for",
      "D": "during\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-progress-test/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Progress Test"
    },
    "answer": "since"
  },
  {
    "id": "7a0434be-c283-47cf-8e85-5f73d725fd26",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "On the day of our 25th wedding anniversary, he told 18.Middle-aged people usually regret ______ some of the\nme that we ______ such a wonderful life together. I mistakes of their youth. But what is done is done\nwished he were sincere. forever.",
    "options": {
      "A": "had had A) to commit",
      "B": "had B) the committing",
      "C": "have had C) committing",
      "D": "were having D) that committed"
    },
    "answer": "had had A) to commit"
  },
  {
    "id": "23ab4f43-43c6-404d-bbd2-f45baba37c9b",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "Rasputin ______ responsible for many of the ill-fated 19.______ I like is illegal, immoral or fattening.\nevents that happened during the reign of Czar\nNicholas II in Russia.",
    "options": {
      "A": "Whoever",
      "B": "Whatever\nA) believes to be",
      "C": "Whenever\nB) was believed to have been",
      "D": "That\nC) they believed him to be"
    },
    "answer": "Whatever\nA) believes to be"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb358bb1-0942-48fb-8e14-eb1227525976",
    "source": "grammar",
    "url": "file://bank_exercises\\grammar\\721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com.pdf",
    "crawl_date": "2025-06-14T12:10:14.370482",
    "type": "grammar",
    "name": "721_self-study-guide-progress-test_englishtestsonline.com",
    "level": null,
    "question": "I ______ to buying green jeans and wearing them to\nD) was believing to be\nwork!",
    "options": {
      "A": "used",
      "B": "did not use",
      "C": "used not",
      "D": "am still not used\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-progress-test/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Progress Test"
    },
    "answer": "am still not used\nBy visiting the link below, you can access the online version of this test and see the most recent updates.\nhttps://www.englishtestsonline.com/self-study-guide-progress-test/\nmoc.enilnostsethsilgne.www\nSelf Study Guide - Progress Test"
  }
]